<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://mediaunmasked.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://mediaunmasked.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-04-22T20:55:18+00:00</updated><id>https://mediaunmasked.com/</id><title type="html">Media Unmasked</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Surface Pro 3 review</title><link href="https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/surface-pro-3-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Surface Pro 3 review" /><published>2016-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/surface-pro-3-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/surface-pro-3-review/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;surface-pro-3&quot;&gt;Surface Pro 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1QlJy41&quot;&gt;Surface Pro 3&lt;/a&gt; is a lightweight tablet that is powerful enough to replace both your laptop and your tablet. It features a pressure sensitive pen, a 12 inch touchscreen, and a detachable, backlit keyboard. In Microsoft’s reveal, the big message they wanted to convey was that this device is meant to replace your laptop and tablet. With a full Windows 10 operating system, the Surface Pro 3 can run any application that you would on your laptop. Microsoft hopes that the Surface Pro 3 will replace your tablet and laptop; they hope to replace your main entertainment device and productivity device. I respect its ambition and think it has accomplished what it has set out to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Microsoft’s next model in the Surface line, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/20PIKMv&quot;&gt;Surface Pro 4&lt;/a&gt;, is released. If you’re looking into getting a Surface, both tablets are very similar, so much of what I say about the 3 can be said about the 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-the-box&quot;&gt;In the box&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;collection with-header&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;
    Surface Pro 3
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;
    Surface Pen
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;
    36W Power supply
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;
    Quick start guide &amp;amp; safety warranty documents
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;specifications&quot;&gt;Specifications&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;striped&quot;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Screen size&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      12&quot;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Resolution&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      2160 x 1440 px (3:2 aspect ratio)
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Dimensions&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      11.5&quot; x 7.93&quot; x 0.3&quot;
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Battery life&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      9 hours (internet browsing)
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Weight&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      1.76lbs (800 grams)
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Storage&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      64GB/128GB with 4GB RAM or&lt;br /&gt;256GB/512GB with 8GB RAM
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Processor&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      4th generation Intel Core i3, i5, or i7
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Ports&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      USB 3.0, microSD card reader, headset jack, mini DisplayPort, and a cover port (for the keyboard)
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Camera&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      5.0 megapixel rear- and front-facing cameras, stereo microphones, and stereo speakers
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Sensors&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Ambient light sensor, accelerometer, gyroscope, and magnetometer
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;model-choices&quot;&gt;Model choices&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They offer 5 different models and, as expected the middle one will probably be the most popular, but when deciding which one I was going to buy, I asked &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/surface&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow&quot;&gt;reddit.com/r/surface&lt;/a&gt; which processor they were going to get (either the i5 or i7, both with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage). With over 200 respondents, the i5 won – partially due to the earlier ship date and the $250 price difference. I also asked about what color of keyboard they were going to get. Here are the results:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/vmOydpt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Surface pro 3 &amp;amp; 4 model differences&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, the lower-end Surface tablets will accomplish what most people need them to do. If you’re wanting to use more resource-demanding software like Premiere, Photoshop, or some games, then you’ll need the better processor and RAM.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has really been pushing the fact that the Surface Pro 3 will replace your laptop, but they sell it without a keyboard! I know you can use the on-screen keyboard, but to compete with any serious laptop, you need a physical keyboard, which will run you another $130. There is a few different colors you can choose from, which is nice. However, the blue touch cover is exclusive to Best Buy and the red touch cover is exclusive to Microsoft.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/TG2QzIn.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Surface pro 3 &amp;amp; 4 keyboard color choices&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-pen-wacom-vs-n-trig&quot;&gt;The pen: Wacom vs N-Trig&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charles Gbadamosi of TickTakashi reviewed the technical aspects of this tablet in regards to the pen and the technology behind it. Initially, when the news that Wacom was no longer the tech behind Microsoft’s Surface, many people seemed upset because of two reasons: N-Trig’s past technology and pressure sensitivity levels. However, Charles points out the insignificance of the sensitivity number:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When drawing with a Brush size that is lower than 256, there is no difference in sensitivity between Wacom and N-Trig. Digitizer companies use pressure levels in the same way that many tech companies use specs: they count on a lack of public understanding in order to justify expensive upgrades that are largely unnecessary. 256 vs 512 vs 1024 vs 2048 is, for the most part, just marketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To elaborate, he says that the pressure sensitivity of 256 is usually only important if you’re using brush sizes larger than 256 (for blown up images on a billboard, for example).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gaming&quot;&gt;Gaming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Games look stunning on a 2160 x 1440 resolution screen, but there are a lot of games that the processor in the Surface can’t handle. However, you can use Steam’s in-home streaming service to stream games from a more powerful computer, like a desktop computer, to your less powerful Surface. The quality of this will depend on your network speed as well as the resolution of your host computer. Still, being able to stream a resource-hungry game to the Surface Pro 3 with low-latency is amazing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using my SP3 almost daily since I got it over a year ago and it has been essential at college, and convenient at home. As a visual communication major, it was the most appropriate &lt;em&gt;laptop&lt;/em&gt; that I could get (and would again in a heartbeat). I highly recommend the Surface (tablet, book, etc.) for students, people who travel, people who draw, and anyone who needs a good performance out of a laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;cta&quot; style=&quot;background: url(&amp;quot;https://i.imgur.com/EuacwPo.jpg&amp;quot;) center center; height: 475px&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1QlJy41&quot; class=&quot;waves-effect waves-light btn-large brown&quot;&gt;Check price on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Surface Pro 3 The Surface Pro 3 is a lightweight tablet that is powerful enough to replace both your laptop and your tablet. It features a pressure sensitive pen, a 12 inch touchscreen, and a detachable, backlit keyboard. In Microsoft’s reveal, the big message they wanted to convey was that this device is meant to replace your laptop and tablet. With a full Windows 10 operating system, the Surface Pro 3 can run any application that you would on your laptop. Microsoft hopes that the Surface Pro 3 will replace your tablet and laptop; they hope to replace your main entertainment device and productivity device. I respect its ambition and think it has accomplished what it has set out to do. Update: Microsoft’s next model in the Surface line, the Surface Pro 4, is released. If you’re looking into getting a Surface, both tablets are very similar, so much of what I say about the 3 can be said about the 4. In the box Surface Pro 3 Surface Pen 36W Power supply Quick start guide &amp;amp; safety warranty documents Specifications Screen size 12&quot; Resolution 2160 x 1440 px (3:2 aspect ratio) Dimensions 11.5&quot; x 7.93&quot; x 0.3&quot; Battery life 9 hours (internet browsing) Weight 1.76lbs (800 grams) Storage 64GB/128GB with 4GB RAM or256GB/512GB with 8GB RAM Processor 4th generation Intel Core i3, i5, or i7 Ports USB 3.0, microSD card reader, headset jack, mini DisplayPort, and a cover port (for the keyboard) Camera 5.0 megapixel rear- and front-facing cameras, stereo microphones, and stereo speakers Sensors Ambient light sensor, accelerometer, gyroscope, and magnetometer Model choices They offer 5 different models and, as expected the middle one will probably be the most popular, but when deciding which one I was going to buy, I asked reddit.com/r/surface which processor they were going to get (either the i5 or i7, both with 8GB of RAM and 256GB of storage). With over 200 respondents, the i5 won – partially due to the earlier ship date and the $250 price difference. I also asked about what color of keyboard they were going to get. Here are the results: At the end of the day, the lower-end Surface tablets will accomplish what most people need them to do. If you’re wanting to use more resource-demanding software like Premiere, Photoshop, or some games, then you’ll need the better processor and RAM. Microsoft has really been pushing the fact that the Surface Pro 3 will replace your laptop, but they sell it without a keyboard! I know you can use the on-screen keyboard, but to compete with any serious laptop, you need a physical keyboard, which will run you another $130. There is a few different colors you can choose from, which is nice. However, the blue touch cover is exclusive to Best Buy and the red touch cover is exclusive to Microsoft. The pen: Wacom vs N-Trig Charles Gbadamosi of TickTakashi reviewed the technical aspects of this tablet in regards to the pen and the technology behind it. Initially, when the news that Wacom was no longer the tech behind Microsoft’s Surface, many people seemed upset because of two reasons: N-Trig’s past technology and pressure sensitivity levels. However, Charles points out the insignificance of the sensitivity number: When drawing with a Brush size that is lower than 256, there is no difference in sensitivity between Wacom and N-Trig. Digitizer companies use pressure levels in the same way that many tech companies use specs: they count on a lack of public understanding in order to justify expensive upgrades that are largely unnecessary. 256 vs 512 vs 1024 vs 2048 is, for the most part, just marketing. To elaborate, he says that the pressure sensitivity of 256 is usually only important if you’re using brush sizes larger than 256 (for blown up images on a billboard, for example). Gaming Games look stunning on a 2160 x 1440 resolution screen, but there are a lot of games that the processor in the Surface can’t handle. However, you can use Steam’s in-home streaming service to stream games from a more powerful computer, like a desktop computer, to your less powerful Surface. The quality of this will depend on your network speed as well as the resolution of your host computer. Still, being able to stream a resource-hungry game to the Surface Pro 3 with low-latency is amazing! Conclusion I’ve been using my SP3 almost daily since I got it over a year ago and it has been essential at college, and convenient at home. As a visual communication major, it was the most appropriate laptop that I could get (and would again in a heartbeat). I highly recommend the Surface (tablet, book, etc.) for students, people who travel, people who draw, and anyone who needs a good performance out of a laptop. Check price on Amazon</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://mediaunmasked.com/assets/2016/02/sp3.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">OnePlus One phone review</title><link href="https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/oneplus-one-phone-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="OnePlus One phone review" /><published>2016-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/oneplus-one-phone-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/oneplus-one-phone-review/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;oneplus-one&quot;&gt;OnePlus One&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever since my first phone went through the washer, I searched far and wide for a phone that was powerful and big enough to do the many things I wanted in a phone and still fit in my pocket and hand comfortably. After hearing about the OnePlus One, I knew it was the phone for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The more I searched, the more I found myself liking the flagship phones like the Samsung Galaxy Note, S6, HTC One, LG G4, etc. These phones all cost much more than I was willing to spend, so I almost settled for the established Motorola Moto G, which is probably the best bang-for-your-buck phone at under $200. Then, I found a couple YouTube videos on a little phone called the OnePlus One. The company is called OnePlus, and their first phone model is the One.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Since the One’s successful release, OnePlus have created &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2ox5eqX&quot;&gt;a few other models&lt;/a&gt; to maintain their &lt;em&gt;Flagship killer&lt;/em&gt; status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/2kiVh6x.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;OnePlus One high quality phone review&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;specs&quot;&gt;Specs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;striped&quot;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Price&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      $300
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Dimensions&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      152.9 x 75.9 x 8.9 mm
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Weight&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      5.71 ounces (162 g)
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Resolution&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      1080p (401 PPI)
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Screen size&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      1.5 in.
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Battery&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      3100mAh (iPhone 6 is 1810mAh for comparison)
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;RAM&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      3GB DDR3
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;CPU&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Snapdragon 801 2.5 GHz Quad-Core
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;GPU&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Adreno 330, 578MHz
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Storage&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      64 GB or 16 GB
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Color&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Sandstone black (64 GB) or silk white (16 GB)
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Camera&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      13 MP (back) 5 MP (front)
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;in-the-box&quot;&gt;In the box&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a company that touts not spending much on marketing to pass its savings on to the user (which is great for those of us who find out about the phone), the product box, website, and overall design of the phone is simple, clean, and beautiful. In the box, you get the phone, a USB charger (that seemed slightly wider than other USB inputs I’ve used, but still fit) with a wall adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design&quot;&gt;Design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pull-left inline s12 m4&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/gs0OgBo.png&quot; alt=&quot;OnePlus One phone quality felt material back case&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The back has a material like no other phone I’ve felt before with a somewhat &lt;em&gt;felt&lt;/em&gt; material feeling. It’s nice to touch, but I bought a cheap case to go with mine. Not necessary, but it helps keep the phone clean and adds a little protection. I also got a strong screen protector in case I inevitably drop it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both models have a near bevel-less design with the standard capacitive buttons on the bottom that can be used or have the option to have buttons on the screen in the software, which is Oxygen OS, replacing what was initially on the One: Cyanogen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three microphones are placed throughout the phone to help isolate your voice and reduce background noise. The sound quality on the One is what I expect from a modern phone - nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple things like double-tapping the screen to wake your phone or drawing a simple image on your screen to open a specific app really enhance your overall experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The phone itself fits nicely in my skinny/normal-sized hands with the buttons easily accessible when held with one hand (they are lower than other phones and the sleep button is on the side opposite the volume rocker, instead of on top).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, OnePlus has done a great job designing the One as a daily driver. Great battery life, size (and feel), and experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;features&quot;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;otg&quot;&gt;OTG&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My previous phone hadn’t had OTG support, so I made sure my new phone would so I could use any USB device, such as the output video on a video transmitter (for RC FPV flight with Google Cardboard and my phone), a DSLR video signal (to use as an external monitor), a keyboard, mouse, USB storage, etc. If you have a camera, phone, or VR phone holder like Google Cardboard that uses NFC technology, the OnePlus One will work with it. The One also supports 4G, bluetooth, Miracast, GPS, and most (or even more) features that you’d find on any other &lt;em&gt;flagship&lt;/em&gt; phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;gps&quot;&gt;GPS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I specifically wanted a pretty powerful phone for its potential use of features. We live in a time where our phones can do so much and, for specific people, replace other gadgets. For example, most phones have GPS built into them, so we can type in a location into Google Maps and get turn-by-turn navigation to our destination. This basically replaces the need for a dedicated GPS device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fpv-virtual-reality-and-video-monitor&quot;&gt;FPV, virtual reality, and video monitor&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phones are essentially just monitors. Some people have dedicated monitors like the ones from Oculus, to be able to experience the new field of virtual reality for gaming or the video goggles made by Fatshark for FPV flight. Much of the hardware and software (games) are still being developed for this new wave of technology. Some companies offer dedicated head mounts for your phone, which cuts down on cost and makes sense, since they are essentially the same thing as what you get from the dedicated monitors (to an extent). Google even released their own version of these phone-mounts called &lt;a href=&quot;https://vr.google.com/cardboard/&quot;&gt;Google Cardboard&lt;/a&gt;. You can buy pre-cut kits on eBay, lenses and magnets included for under $5. This, in combination with software like Limelight and Trinus Gyre enables you to play PC games with a high-resolution VR set, for cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the same hardware, we can eliminate yet another $300 set of dedicated video goggles like the ones from Fatshark, while being able to fly an RC helicopter (also known as a &lt;em&gt;drone&lt;/em&gt;) for filming or fun. These goggles are specifically designed for this purpose (offering different features), but since it’s just a monitor at its core, we can use an app on our phone and a video receiver that plugs in via OTG technology to show the video on our phones. Still much cheaper than the dedicated goggles!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we’re at it, why not use the OnePlus One alongside my DSLR camera as an external monitor? With the bigger display and another cheap wire mount, I can attach it to the camera body or even a 3-axis gimbal to give me both what’s being captured (with a slight delay) and controls of the camera settings without needing to touch the camera (specifically helpful if used with a gimbal).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;games-movies-and-web-development&quot;&gt;Games, movies, and web development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pull-right inline s12 m4&quot;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/4q39wgN.png&quot; alt=&quot;OnePlus One phone review web browsing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I don’t play many games on my phone (I have a computer for that), the ones I have played run smooth and look amazing on the 1080p display. With a &lt;i&gt;spider&lt;/i&gt; wire mount, my phone can be hung or rested from different positions while I watch a movie or use it while developing a website for mobile screens (live reload / browsersync). I even found a text editor app - so, while not practical, I could do the coding on it with my bluetooth mouse and USB keyboard via the OTG adapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, if you’re looking for a phone to just text, call, and do basic phone stuff, but still want the versatility of a smart phone, I recommend checking out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/20PHLvy&quot;&gt;Moto G&lt;/a&gt;. If you’re like me and are wanting a little more in a phone or have considered getting a “flagship” phone for its power/features (and not its status), then the OnePlus One might be the phone you’ve been looking for. I hope this review has helped save you some money and show you some of the potential that a phone can offer. I’ve had this phone for over a year now and I will say that it is worth the money if you were planning on spending around $300 anyway. It’s the best price for performance that I found when searching for a phone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;cta&quot; style=&quot;background: url(&amp;quot;https://i.imgur.com/nQS2cbI.jpg&amp;quot;) center center; height: 475px&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;//amzn.to/1T78fY9&quot; class=&quot;waves-effect waves-light btn-large white red-text&quot;&gt;Check price on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">OnePlus One Ever since my first phone went through the washer, I searched far and wide for a phone that was powerful and big enough to do the many things I wanted in a phone and still fit in my pocket and hand comfortably. After hearing about the OnePlus One, I knew it was the phone for me. The more I searched, the more I found myself liking the flagship phones like the Samsung Galaxy Note, S6, HTC One, LG G4, etc. These phones all cost much more than I was willing to spend, so I almost settled for the established Motorola Moto G, which is probably the best bang-for-your-buck phone at under $200. Then, I found a couple YouTube videos on a little phone called the OnePlus One. The company is called OnePlus, and their first phone model is the One. Update: Since the One’s successful release, OnePlus have created a few other models to maintain their Flagship killer status. Specs Price $300 Dimensions 152.9 x 75.9 x 8.9 mm Weight 5.71 ounces (162 g) Resolution 1080p (401 PPI) Screen size 1.5 in. Battery 3100mAh (iPhone 6 is 1810mAh for comparison) RAM 3GB DDR3 CPU Snapdragon 801 2.5 GHz Quad-Core GPU Adreno 330, 578MHz Storage 64 GB or 16 GB Color Sandstone black (64 GB) or silk white (16 GB) Camera 13 MP (back) 5 MP (front) In the box For a company that touts not spending much on marketing to pass its savings on to the user (which is great for those of us who find out about the phone), the product box, website, and overall design of the phone is simple, clean, and beautiful. In the box, you get the phone, a USB charger (that seemed slightly wider than other USB inputs I’ve used, but still fit) with a wall adapter. Design The back has a material like no other phone I’ve felt before with a somewhat felt material feeling. It’s nice to touch, but I bought a cheap case to go with mine. Not necessary, but it helps keep the phone clean and adds a little protection. I also got a strong screen protector in case I inevitably drop it. Both models have a near bevel-less design with the standard capacitive buttons on the bottom that can be used or have the option to have buttons on the screen in the software, which is Oxygen OS, replacing what was initially on the One: Cyanogen. Three microphones are placed throughout the phone to help isolate your voice and reduce background noise. The sound quality on the One is what I expect from a modern phone - nothing more. Simple things like double-tapping the screen to wake your phone or drawing a simple image on your screen to open a specific app really enhance your overall experience. The phone itself fits nicely in my skinny/normal-sized hands with the buttons easily accessible when held with one hand (they are lower than other phones and the sleep button is on the side opposite the volume rocker, instead of on top). Overall, OnePlus has done a great job designing the One as a daily driver. Great battery life, size (and feel), and experience. Features OTG My previous phone hadn’t had OTG support, so I made sure my new phone would so I could use any USB device, such as the output video on a video transmitter (for RC FPV flight with Google Cardboard and my phone), a DSLR video signal (to use as an external monitor), a keyboard, mouse, USB storage, etc. If you have a camera, phone, or VR phone holder like Google Cardboard that uses NFC technology, the OnePlus One will work with it. The One also supports 4G, bluetooth, Miracast, GPS, and most (or even more) features that you’d find on any other flagship phone. GPS I specifically wanted a pretty powerful phone for its potential use of features. We live in a time where our phones can do so much and, for specific people, replace other gadgets. For example, most phones have GPS built into them, so we can type in a location into Google Maps and get turn-by-turn navigation to our destination. This basically replaces the need for a dedicated GPS device. FPV, virtual reality, and video monitor Phones are essentially just monitors. Some people have dedicated monitors like the ones from Oculus, to be able to experience the new field of virtual reality for gaming or the video goggles made by Fatshark for FPV flight. Much of the hardware and software (games) are still being developed for this new wave of technology. Some companies offer dedicated head mounts for your phone, which cuts down on cost and makes sense, since they are essentially the same thing as what you get from the dedicated monitors (to an extent). Google even released their own version of these phone-mounts called Google Cardboard. You can buy pre-cut kits on eBay, lenses and magnets included for under $5. This, in combination with software like Limelight and Trinus Gyre enables you to play PC games with a high-resolution VR set, for cheap. With the same hardware, we can eliminate yet another $300 set of dedicated video goggles like the ones from Fatshark, while being able to fly an RC helicopter (also known as a drone) for filming or fun. These goggles are specifically designed for this purpose (offering different features), but since it’s just a monitor at its core, we can use an app on our phone and a video receiver that plugs in via OTG technology to show the video on our phones. Still much cheaper than the dedicated goggles! While we’re at it, why not use the OnePlus One alongside my DSLR camera as an external monitor? With the bigger display and another cheap wire mount, I can attach it to the camera body or even a 3-axis gimbal to give me both what’s being captured (with a slight delay) and controls of the camera settings without needing to touch the camera (specifically helpful if used with a gimbal). Games, movies, and web development Although I don’t play many games on my phone (I have a computer for that), the ones I have played run smooth and look amazing on the 1080p display. With a spider wire mount, my phone can be hung or rested from different positions while I watch a movie or use it while developing a website for mobile screens (live reload / browsersync). I even found a text editor app - so, while not practical, I could do the coding on it with my bluetooth mouse and USB keyboard via the OTG adapter. Conclusion Again, if you’re looking for a phone to just text, call, and do basic phone stuff, but still want the versatility of a smart phone, I recommend checking out the Moto G. If you’re like me and are wanting a little more in a phone or have considered getting a “flagship” phone for its power/features (and not its status), then the OnePlus One might be the phone you’ve been looking for. I hope this review has helped save you some money and show you some of the potential that a phone can offer. I’ve had this phone for over a year now and I will say that it is worth the money if you were planning on spending around $300 anyway. It’s the best price for performance that I found when searching for a phone. Check price on Amazon</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://mediaunmasked.com/assets/2016/02/2kiVh6x.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">How to do FPV on your phone</title><link href="https://mediaunmasked.com/tutorials/fpv-with-your-phone/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to do FPV on your phone" /><published>2016-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://mediaunmasked.com/tutorials/fpv-with-your-phone</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mediaunmasked.com/tutorials/fpv-with-your-phone/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;radio-controlled-first-person-view&quot;&gt;Radio controlled first person view&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We live in a fantastic time (compared to the past, not the future), and part of what makes this year so great is the ability to pilot an aircraft the size of a tarantula for under $50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the fastest growing areas of technology is &lt;em&gt;drones&lt;/em&gt;, or RC helicopters. They, and other RC vehicles, have been around for many years, but have recently grown in popularity with the combined implementation of affordability, ease-ability, and on-board cameras for filming or first-person-view flight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I’ve had my fair share of RC as a child, these introductions also piqued my interest as an adult. So, I built a crude tricopter out of wood and slapped a GoPro on it and became one of the other millions of people to upload their shaky footage to YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/e9NbrR9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FPV Youtube search results&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While getting a bird’s eye view of your house is fun, I began to further explore the idea of flying with a live video feed like I’ve seen other people do. I later bought a pair of &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1mz8U6G&quot;&gt;Fatshark FPV video goggles&lt;/a&gt; that basically act as a monitor (attached to your face) with a dedicated location for proprietary video receiver and head-tracking modules — neat, huh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hardware--software&quot;&gt;Hardware &amp;amp; software&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col s12 m4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/mfclBWb.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;LaserBGC wireless USB module receiver for Fatshark FPV headset goggles&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col s12 m8&quot;&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Today, technology is rampant and the amount of different phones and drones is staggering. Phones range from $20 to $700+ and all offer similar&lt;i&gt;ish&lt;/i&gt; features. The same can be said about RC multirotor helicopters, but they seem to be dropping in price much faster than phones.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Regardless, to get a decent setup, you can easily spend upwards of &lt;b&gt;$1000+&lt;/b&gt; to get in the sky. &lt;i&gt;Or not&lt;/i&gt;. Since phones are basically a tiny display, why not use it to fly a quadcopter? Here's a list of items, software, etc. I'll be using to &lt;b&gt;get FPV on a phone&lt;/b&gt; for much cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Update:&lt;/b&gt; LaserBGC now has a receiver module that plugs directly into your phone (phone still needs to support OTG), removing the need for a dedicated OTG cable.
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;collection with-header&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-header&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;
      Video Rx (Receiver)
    &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;
    Android phone with &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.homesoft.otgtroubshooter&amp;#038;hl=en&quot;&gt;OTG support&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1mzcfCK&quot;&gt;Video receiver module&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://laserbgc.com/index.php?route=product/product&amp;#038;product_id=82&quot;&gt;Video receiver USB module&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1HwM5El&quot;&gt;OTG cable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;or&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://laserbgc.com/index.php?route=product/product&amp;#038;path=67&amp;#038;product_id=83&quot;&gt;Modular receiver for Android&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1HwLYZl&quot;&gt;Google Cardboard&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2nCrmRm&quot;&gt;VR Box&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=labsp.android.viewer&quot;&gt;FPViewer&lt;/a&gt; App
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;Optional:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1HwMgze&quot;&gt;Fatshark diopter corrective lenses&lt;/a&gt; (if you're nearsighted)
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-header&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;
      Video Tx (Transmitter)
    &lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1mzeC8o&quot;&gt;Video transmitter&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 
    
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;
    &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1PTRmhv&quot;&gt;Video camera&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;Optional:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/20SE0sP&quot;&gt;Battery for video Tx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Otherwise, solder into your power distribution from your vehicle
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;
    &lt;b&gt;Optional:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/20SExLf&quot;&gt;Lipo battery charger&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/20SECi7&quot;&gt;protective bag&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;see-it-in-action&quot;&gt;See it in action&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/et3BG5o.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FPV quadcopter racing on your phone&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;transmitter&quot;&gt;Transmitter&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure the video transmitter and receiver you get run on the same frequency. In this example, you’ll need to get a Fatshark-fitted module to fit on the USB module. I use the 1.3GHz bandwidth so it penetrates structures or 5.8GHz for distance. Also, ensure that you have the right voltage battery for the job. 11.1V (3 cell) is common.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/YCx6qTB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FPV video transmitter battery&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/mTeMVMi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;FPV video transmitter battery&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, make sure the video transmitter has an antenna on it before proceeding. I’ve heard it can fry the insides if it doesn’t have one on the transmitter. Not including an antenna on the receiver is okay, but it’s got reduced effectiveness. Simply plug in the battery to the video transmitter and it should be on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some quads power the transmitter/camera with the quad’s main battery, which certainly simplifies it. These things can get warm, so when you place it on a vehicle, be sure to allow for some air flow. Racing quadcopters are usually cut to an optimized size and it should be obvious where to place the battery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re powering the transmitter with a separate power supply, connect the battery to the transmitter and the transmitter to the video output port on the camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;receiver&quot;&gt;Receiver&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/pVkuLDT.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Video receiver for FPV on your phone&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;center-align&quot;&gt;
  &lt;video autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source type=&quot;video/webm&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/2SvN1os.webm&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/2SvN1os.mp4&quot; /&gt;
  &lt;/video&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you bought the USB adapter instead of the one for your phone, just plug the USB module into your phone with the OTG cable and open the FPView (or similar) app. Otherwise, plug it in and start flying!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/09N6udO.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;OTG on the go cable adapter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tada! Now you have an external monitor that you can use to fly FPV and use to record as an on-board camera. With a phone head strap like Google Cardboard or comparable devices like VR Box, you can either fly with it on your head or looking down at the screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cardboard&quot;&gt;Cardboard&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, Google implemented some free plans so anyone can turn their phone into a (virtual reality) headset! With the help of Chinese manufacturers and free shipping, you can get a precut kit with the magnet, eye pieces, and other required parts on ebay or amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/eFjjizt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Goole Cardboard FPV setup with phone as monitor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing particularly new or revolutionary, but by using your phone and cardboard, you’re saving $300+ that would have been spent on a dedicated set of video goggles. I’m pretty sure the latency is comparable; it is certainly responsive enough to be able to fly with. But your phone can also call, text, game (virtual reality), etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;center-align&quot;&gt;
  &lt;video autoplay=&quot;&quot; loop=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;source type=&quot;video/webm&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/oXilp86.webm&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;source type=&quot;video/mp4&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/oXilp86.mp4&quot; /&gt;
  &amp;lt;/video
&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;gt;
&lt;/video&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Radio controlled first person view We live in a fantastic time (compared to the past, not the future), and part of what makes this year so great is the ability to pilot an aircraft the size of a tarantula for under $50. One of the fastest growing areas of technology is drones, or RC helicopters. They, and other RC vehicles, have been around for many years, but have recently grown in popularity with the combined implementation of affordability, ease-ability, and on-board cameras for filming or first-person-view flight. Although I’ve had my fair share of RC as a child, these introductions also piqued my interest as an adult. So, I built a crude tricopter out of wood and slapped a GoPro on it and became one of the other millions of people to upload their shaky footage to YouTube. While getting a bird’s eye view of your house is fun, I began to further explore the idea of flying with a live video feed like I’ve seen other people do. I later bought a pair of Fatshark FPV video goggles that basically act as a monitor (attached to your face) with a dedicated location for proprietary video receiver and head-tracking modules — neat, huh? Hardware &amp;amp; software Today, technology is rampant and the amount of different phones and drones is staggering. Phones range from $20 to $700+ and all offer similarish features. The same can be said about RC multirotor helicopters, but they seem to be dropping in price much faster than phones. Regardless, to get a decent setup, you can easily spend upwards of $1000+ to get in the sky. Or not. Since phones are basically a tiny display, why not use it to fly a quadcopter? Here's a list of items, software, etc. I'll be using to get FPV on a phone for much cheaper. Update: LaserBGC now has a receiver module that plugs directly into your phone (phone still needs to support OTG), removing the need for a dedicated OTG cable. Video Rx (Receiver) Android phone with OTG support Video receiver module Video receiver USB module &amp;amp; OTG cableorModular receiver for Android Google Cardboard or VR Box FPViewer App Optional: Fatshark diopter corrective lenses (if you're nearsighted) Video Tx (Transmitter) Video transmitter Video camera Optional: Battery for video TxOtherwise, solder into your power distribution from your vehicle Optional: Lipo battery charger and protective bag See it in action Transmitter Make sure the video transmitter and receiver you get run on the same frequency. In this example, you’ll need to get a Fatshark-fitted module to fit on the USB module. I use the 1.3GHz bandwidth so it penetrates structures or 5.8GHz for distance. Also, ensure that you have the right voltage battery for the job. 11.1V (3 cell) is common. First, make sure the video transmitter has an antenna on it before proceeding. I’ve heard it can fry the insides if it doesn’t have one on the transmitter. Not including an antenna on the receiver is okay, but it’s got reduced effectiveness. Simply plug in the battery to the video transmitter and it should be on. Some quads power the transmitter/camera with the quad’s main battery, which certainly simplifies it. These things can get warm, so when you place it on a vehicle, be sure to allow for some air flow. Racing quadcopters are usually cut to an optimized size and it should be obvious where to place the battery. If you’re powering the transmitter with a separate power supply, connect the battery to the transmitter and the transmitter to the video output port on the camera. Receiver If you bought the USB adapter instead of the one for your phone, just plug the USB module into your phone with the OTG cable and open the FPView (or similar) app. Otherwise, plug it in and start flying! Tada! Now you have an external monitor that you can use to fly FPV and use to record as an on-board camera. With a phone head strap like Google Cardboard or comparable devices like VR Box, you can either fly with it on your head or looking down at the screen. Cardboard Luckily, Google implemented some free plans so anyone can turn their phone into a (virtual reality) headset! With the help of Chinese manufacturers and free shipping, you can get a precut kit with the magnet, eye pieces, and other required parts on ebay or amazon. Nothing particularly new or revolutionary, but by using your phone and cardboard, you’re saving $300+ that would have been spent on a dedicated set of video goggles. I’m pretty sure the latency is comparable; it is certainly responsive enough to be able to fly with. But your phone can also call, text, game (virtual reality), etc. &amp;lt;/video &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;gt;</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://mediaunmasked.com/assets/2016/02/nrGgCUM.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Comparing Codepen, JSFiddle, JSBin, Plunkr, CSSDeck, Liveweave, Dabblet</title><link href="https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/comparing-codepen-jsfiddle-cssdeck-liveweave-jsbin-dabblet/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Comparing Codepen, JSFiddle, JSBin, Plunkr, CSSDeck, Liveweave, Dabblet" /><published>2016-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/comparing-codepen-jsfiddle-cssdeck-liveweave-jsbin-dabblet</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/comparing-codepen-jsfiddle-cssdeck-liveweave-jsbin-dabblet/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-is-a-code-playground&quot;&gt;What is a code playground?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codepen, JSFiddle, JS Bin, Dabblet, CSS Deck, and Liveweave are HTML, CSS and JavaScript playgrounds, meaning that you can type in your HTML, CSS and JavaScript to troubleshoot, mess around with some code, or quickly write HTML CSS, and Javascript. These sites are the leading playgrounds for front-end developers and in this article I hope to point out some pros and cons of each and conclude an overall winner. If anyone is familiar with C++, these playgrounds are like drivers – you use them to avoid creating a mess of code that you can’t troubleshoot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These code playgrounds are reviewed in no particular order. If you want to read my overall thoughts among them all, read the last section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;Codepen&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;Codepen.io&lt;/a&gt; is a nice and sleak code playground that lets you mess with HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript (as they all playgrounds do).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p data-height=&quot;268&quot; data-theme-id=&quot;0&quot; data-slug-hash=&quot;wMNzLy&quot; data-default-tab=&quot;result&quot; data-user=&quot;ispal&quot; class=&quot;codepen&quot;&gt;
  See the Pen &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/ispal/pen/wMNzLy/&quot;&gt;CSS Rolling Loader&lt;/a&gt; by Irko Palenius (&lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/ispal&quot;&gt;@ispal&lt;/a&gt;) on &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io&quot;&gt;CodePen&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Codepen has a liveview that is automatically updated when you type and allows for three major layouts. These layouts reload the page when you click them and you can save your code to your account but must buy the pro version to get any private projects. The pro version also enables a live view that automatically updates on different devices as you type, asset hosting which allows you to use your images and other files for your site, a collaborative mode which enables shared coding, unlimited embed themes, “professor mode” which enables a full-screen for presentations, private pens and multiple external resources you can link to. You can read the entire list of benefits &lt;a href=&quot;http://codepen.io/pro&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jsbin&quot;&gt;JSBin&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;jsbin.com&quot;&gt;JS Bin&lt;/a&gt; is different from the others by the way of embedding. Sure, others have embeddable code, but you have to click a link on the embedded app to go to that particular site to alter the code in any way. I think it’s a much nicer sentiment to allow the code to be edited on the page it’s embedded into. JSbin also offers a free &lt;em&gt;codecasting&lt;/em&gt; feature that Codepin charges for and, unlike CSSDeck, is live. Enter JS Bin! JS Bin lets you embed and edit the code right on the website it’s embedded on. Go ahead and try changing the code below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jsbin.com/vafutoleyu/embed?html,output&quot;&gt;JS Bin on jsbin.com&lt;/a&gt;{.jsbin-embed}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;plunker&quot;&gt;Plunker&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://plnkr.co/&quot;&gt;Plunker&lt;/a&gt; allows for multiple files to be added to your project. This is helpful when trying to make more than just a simple demo. It features real time code collaboration and live preview updating, code linting, and the project is open source under the MIT license.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, the embedded code cannot be edited directly. You need to open it on plunker to mess with the code example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cssdeck&quot;&gt;CSSDeck&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://cssdeck.com&quot;&gt;CSS Deck&lt;/a&gt; shares many of the capabilities of the other code playgrounds, but offers a few more, while maintaining the low price of free. You can sign in with social media, including Github, as others have to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/t1Mczuy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once logged into CSS Deck, you’ll find it’s layout is similar to the others, particularly JS Bin, but the design is a bit more sleek, in my opinion. You’ve got sections for HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and then an area for the result. You can choose to include or exclude certain elements, similar to the embed below. It offers two different formats though; you can either put the code areas on the left or on the bottom. CSS Deck offers HTML, CSS, and JavaScript preprocessors, which is something the others don’t offer. You can set your code to private or public all in the settings of each project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/8jRP75G.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, CSS Deck offers the ability to record your process for others to review later on. They call them codecasts; go ahead and watch this one to see how it works. As with the others, you can fork (copy) any public project. However, CSS Deck offers a nice way to embed the code into a website (see below), which can be nice if you have a blog and share what you learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre class=&quot;_cssdeck_embed&quot; data-pane=&quot;output&quot; data-user=&quot;rishabhp&quot; data-href=&quot;css3-flickr-loading-animation-spinner&quot; data-version=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dabblet&quot;&gt;Dabblet&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dabblet.com&quot;&gt;Dabblet&lt;/a&gt; feels much more design oriented than the others. I’m not saying the other code playgrounds look bad, but I really appreciate dabblet’s look. It’s the small things, like giving a visual representation of a dimension when you hover your mouse over the number, or show the color and other parameters when you hover over the word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, the small things make me really want to like dabblet, like how they link to a website that validates your code. But, at the same time, the small things that other services offer and dabblet does not somewhat frustrates me because I like the design of this one so much. For example, you can’t resize each section manually. So, one code section gets much smaller screen real estate than the other two, which may be helpful or harmful depending on what project you’re working on. You can embed dabblet by including an iframe with the source of your project. You can also change the layout and which section (HTML/CSS/JS/Result) you want to view at any given moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;liveweave&quot;&gt;Liveweave&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://liveweave.com&quot;&gt;Liveweave&lt;/a&gt; is very similar to the others but has some different features; it has four different layouts that you can pick to suite your size monitor and preferences. However, Liveweave updates the layout without reloading the page and you can actually change the size of each individual cell. A small thing, I know, but I thought it was worth mentioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, embedding Liveweave is possible through an iframe, but it’s not the most responsive layout. If you need to embed code, I recommend using a different playground.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/rO4QfUJ.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liveweave has also got a live preview option which can be turned off it you need it disabled temporarily (for javascript editing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While most playgrounds offer Emmet (formerly called Zen coding), Liveweave requires you to press Ctrl + E (Cmd + E) to activate the action, while the others require you to hit tab (tab is what most editing software uses). There’s also a smart autocompletion and linting logic in the editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/wWf1GT5.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Liveweave offers the ability to download your code as well as a “Tidy-up HTML” feature that will auto-format and clean up your code a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another feature that is unique to Liveweave is the color &amp;amp; palette lab, a reference tool that will help you find or create the right color scheme for your site. As is with the other playgrounds, there is a plethora of externally hosted frameworks that you can reference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/2or81YA.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jsfiddle&quot;&gt;JSFiddle&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From my experience of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/&quot;&gt;stack overflow&lt;/a&gt; forums, &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsfiddle.net&quot;&gt;JSFiddle&lt;/a&gt; is as normal as using Imgur for Reddit. So why use any other if JSFiddle is such a standard?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/T9530ar.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, for one, JS Fiddle doesn’t auto-update when you type. You need to hit Ctrl + E to run the code, which can be tedious if you’re troubleshooting. You can still resize the cells, use external resources, frameworks, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It also expands the options by offering different languages like Coffeescript (a Javascript preprocessor) or SCSS instead of CSS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JS Fiddle has a nice collaboration mode that lets you work on the same section of code with people you’re working with, in real time. You can properly embed a fiddle in your blog by clicking the share dropdown (you need to be logged in to see this option). Below is an example of JS Fiddle’s embed capabilities. Unfortunately, you cannot edit JSFiddle embeds directly (instead, there is a link to jsfiddle.net).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/y7huVZ2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the playgrounds I wrote about certainly have good things about them, so in the end it’s up to you to choose which one you like the best and will go to first. I, personally, will likely use CSS Deck because it offers most of the things I will find myself using. Features that include embedding code that people can edit, simple design, and ease of use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the playgrounds offer the basic necessities to troubleshoot your code and they even have what I would consider add-ons (such as Emmet). In the end, you should try them all, at least for a little bit. You will find features in one that you like over the others and choose from your experience. I know there are more code playgrounds, but I found these to be the most appealing to me.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What is a code playground? Codepen, JSFiddle, JS Bin, Dabblet, CSS Deck, and Liveweave are HTML, CSS and JavaScript playgrounds, meaning that you can type in your HTML, CSS and JavaScript to troubleshoot, mess around with some code, or quickly write HTML CSS, and Javascript. These sites are the leading playgrounds for front-end developers and in this article I hope to point out some pros and cons of each and conclude an overall winner. If anyone is familiar with C++, these playgrounds are like drivers – you use them to avoid creating a mess of code that you can’t troubleshoot. These code playgrounds are reviewed in no particular order. If you want to read my overall thoughts among them all, read the last section. Codepen Codepen.io is a nice and sleak code playground that lets you mess with HTML5, CSS3, and JavaScript (as they all playgrounds do). See the Pen CSS Rolling Loader by Irko Palenius (@ispal) on CodePen. Codepen has a liveview that is automatically updated when you type and allows for three major layouts. These layouts reload the page when you click them and you can save your code to your account but must buy the pro version to get any private projects. The pro version also enables a live view that automatically updates on different devices as you type, asset hosting which allows you to use your images and other files for your site, a collaborative mode which enables shared coding, unlimited embed themes, “professor mode” which enables a full-screen for presentations, private pens and multiple external resources you can link to. You can read the entire list of benefits here. JSBin JS Bin is different from the others by the way of embedding. Sure, others have embeddable code, but you have to click a link on the embedded app to go to that particular site to alter the code in any way. I think it’s a much nicer sentiment to allow the code to be edited on the page it’s embedded into. JSbin also offers a free codecasting feature that Codepin charges for and, unlike CSSDeck, is live. Enter JS Bin! JS Bin lets you embed and edit the code right on the website it’s embedded on. Go ahead and try changing the code below! JS Bin on jsbin.com{.jsbin-embed} Plunker Plunker allows for multiple files to be added to your project. This is helpful when trying to make more than just a simple demo. It features real time code collaboration and live preview updating, code linting, and the project is open source under the MIT license. Unfortunately, the embedded code cannot be edited directly. You need to open it on plunker to mess with the code example. CSSDeck CSS Deck shares many of the capabilities of the other code playgrounds, but offers a few more, while maintaining the low price of free. You can sign in with social media, including Github, as others have to offer. Once logged into CSS Deck, you’ll find it’s layout is similar to the others, particularly JS Bin, but the design is a bit more sleek, in my opinion. You’ve got sections for HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and then an area for the result. You can choose to include or exclude certain elements, similar to the embed below. It offers two different formats though; you can either put the code areas on the left or on the bottom. CSS Deck offers HTML, CSS, and JavaScript preprocessors, which is something the others don’t offer. You can set your code to private or public all in the settings of each project. Interestingly, CSS Deck offers the ability to record your process for others to review later on. They call them codecasts; go ahead and watch this one to see how it works. As with the others, you can fork (copy) any public project. However, CSS Deck offers a nice way to embed the code into a website (see below), which can be nice if you have a blog and share what you learn. Dabblet Dabblet feels much more design oriented than the others. I’m not saying the other code playgrounds look bad, but I really appreciate dabblet’s look. It’s the small things, like giving a visual representation of a dimension when you hover your mouse over the number, or show the color and other parameters when you hover over the word. Again, the small things make me really want to like dabblet, like how they link to a website that validates your code. But, at the same time, the small things that other services offer and dabblet does not somewhat frustrates me because I like the design of this one so much. For example, you can’t resize each section manually. So, one code section gets much smaller screen real estate than the other two, which may be helpful or harmful depending on what project you’re working on. You can embed dabblet by including an iframe with the source of your project. You can also change the layout and which section (HTML/CSS/JS/Result) you want to view at any given moment. Liveweave Liveweave is very similar to the others but has some different features; it has four different layouts that you can pick to suite your size monitor and preferences. However, Liveweave updates the layout without reloading the page and you can actually change the size of each individual cell. A small thing, I know, but I thought it was worth mentioning. As you can see, embedding Liveweave is possible through an iframe, but it’s not the most responsive layout. If you need to embed code, I recommend using a different playground. Liveweave has also got a live preview option which can be turned off it you need it disabled temporarily (for javascript editing). While most playgrounds offer Emmet (formerly called Zen coding), Liveweave requires you to press Ctrl + E (Cmd + E) to activate the action, while the others require you to hit tab (tab is what most editing software uses). There’s also a smart autocompletion and linting logic in the editor. Liveweave offers the ability to download your code as well as a “Tidy-up HTML” feature that will auto-format and clean up your code a bit. Another feature that is unique to Liveweave is the color &amp;amp; palette lab, a reference tool that will help you find or create the right color scheme for your site. As is with the other playgrounds, there is a plethora of externally hosted frameworks that you can reference. JSFiddle From my experience of the stack overflow forums, JSFiddle is as normal as using Imgur for Reddit. So why use any other if JSFiddle is such a standard? Well, for one, JS Fiddle doesn’t auto-update when you type. You need to hit Ctrl + E to run the code, which can be tedious if you’re troubleshooting. You can still resize the cells, use external resources, frameworks, etc. It also expands the options by offering different languages like Coffeescript (a Javascript preprocessor) or SCSS instead of CSS. JS Fiddle has a nice collaboration mode that lets you work on the same section of code with people you’re working with, in real time. You can properly embed a fiddle in your blog by clicking the share dropdown (you need to be logged in to see this option). Below is an example of JS Fiddle’s embed capabilities. Unfortunately, you cannot edit JSFiddle embeds directly (instead, there is a link to jsfiddle.net). Conclusion All the playgrounds I wrote about certainly have good things about them, so in the end it’s up to you to choose which one you like the best and will go to first. I, personally, will likely use CSS Deck because it offers most of the things I will find myself using. Features that include embedding code that people can edit, simple design, and ease of use. All of the playgrounds offer the basic necessities to troubleshoot your code and they even have what I would consider add-ons (such as Emmet). In the end, you should try them all, at least for a little bit. You will find features in one that you like over the others and choose from your experience. I know there are more code playgrounds, but I found these to be the most appealing to me.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://mediaunmasked.com/assets/2016/02/HZlxXt4.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Best (cheap) DSLR lenses</title><link href="https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/best-beginner-lens-on-dslr-cameras-for-photographers-or-videographers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Best (cheap) DSLR lenses" /><published>2016-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-02-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/best-beginner-lens-on-dslr-cameras-for-photographers-or-videographers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/best-beginner-lens-on-dslr-cameras-for-photographers-or-videographers/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-use-do-you-have-for-the-lens&quot;&gt;What use do you have for the lens?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many lenses to choose from the DSLR family and it can be a bit daunting when you don’t know what you’re looking for. Beginner lenses should be cheap and effective - luckily, there are a few out there that fit such criteria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start out, you should assess why you need a lens – will you be shooting animals in nature, portraits, close-ups, or everyday use?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, what is your budget? Often, lenses will cost more than the camera body itself. I want to preface these suggestions by saying that I have owned, used and personally recommend each of the items below. I’m not a professional photographer, but I have done some paid gigs. While these lenses may not be the best glassware ever made, they do create high quality photographs at an affordable, hobbyist-level price range. Before picking the perfect one, you must first examine what you’ll be using the lens for. There are a few major categories when deciding what type of lends you’ll be needing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zoom lens&lt;/strong&gt; – animal, sports, or similar photography&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Macro lens&lt;/strong&gt; – extreme close-up shots&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wide angle lens&lt;/strong&gt; – realty videos and landscape photography&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prime lens&lt;/strong&gt; – no zoom, more crisp focus and image quality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s further examine each style. Each have their benefits for different types of photography. When you consider your use, also keep in mind the quality of glass. For example, I have a prime lens that only cost around $100 and a zoom that cost maybe two or three times that; the prime lens creates a much sharper image and has a lower f-number, allowing for more light and depth of field in the image. Now, to examine the lenses that I would consider the top qualifying for each category:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;zoom-lens--145-55-250mm&quot;&gt;Zoom Lens – $145 55-250mm&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pull-left inline s12 m3&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/IWuB3UY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Canon 55-250mm test shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quality zoom lenses are hard to find due to the amount of glass in them, and thus making them some of the most expensive lenses to choose from. My first zoom was the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1SNjQvZ&quot;&gt;55-250mm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has a closest focal distance of 3.6 feet or 1.1m with image stabilization and autofocus. If light isn’t an issue, this piece of glass can do a great job for its price. The Canon EF-S 55-250mm telephoto lens has an f-number of f/4.0-5.6, allowing an adequate amount of light into the sensor. There are some special offers offered from Amazon, such as a 1 year warranty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;macro-lens--15-extension-tubes&quot;&gt;Macro Lens – $15 Extension Tubes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pull-left inline s12 m3&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/McE18am.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;50mm beginner lens example&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may have not been what you expected, but if you’re beginning into the hobby of photography or videography, I think it’s safe to assume you’re on a little bit of a budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These extension tubes do require having a lens to start with, so you can’t expect to only pay $15 to start taking extreme closeup shots that are super sharp. These extension tubes are relatively simple; they extend your lens from your camera and keep it still, creating a zoomed-in effect that you would only expect to see with a dedicated macro lens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The great thing about these extension tubes is that it turns nearly any of your lenses into a macro lens. It is great with primes that let in a fair amount of light, such as the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1R1A2WP&quot;&gt;50mm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the features won’t be accessible on your lens (if it’s digitally controlled, as many are) while using the extension tubes because the lens itself isn’t physically connected to the camera body. It still takes great photos for a $15 addon! If you are looking for a more professional piece of glassware that’s dedicated to macro photography, check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1R1A94G&quot;&gt;100mm f/2.8 lens&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;wide-angle-lens--300-350-sigma-10-20mm&quot;&gt;Wide Angle Lens – $300-350 Sigma 10-20mm&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pull-right inline s12 m3&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/OusLEXG.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rectilinear lens (not distorted) example&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wide angle lenses can be a bit tricky when looking for the right one because many of them are super expensive and or have a weird effect known as a fish-eye. If you’re looking to make skateboarding videos, music videos, or other types of videos that a GoProesque effect would add to the overall production, you might be interested in something like the Rokinon 8mm F3.5 Fisheye. While you get a weird effect with the lens, it is much wider and has a lower f-number, meaning it will allow more light and create more depth of field. But if you’re looking to minimize distortion and keep a majority of the picture as undistorted as possible, I recommend the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1KhfoTb&quot;&gt;Sigma 10-20mm&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These lenses tend to have little or no barrel or pincushion distortion (they keep straight features straight instead of curving them). However, in these types of lenses, the rectilinear perspective creates things on the sides of the image to appear bigger than they are (almost stretching the outer edges a bit).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pull-left inline s12 m3&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/FOWJOvU.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Curvilinear (fisheye effect) lens example&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This type of lens creates a much more exaggerated wide-angle image that distorts straight lines along the edges into more curvy lines. Initially used to study clouds with their “whole-sky”” point of view, this hemispherical perspective lens adds a very distinct effect to your photographs or video. While not practical for every event, it certainly is worth considering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;clearfix&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;pull-right inline s12 m3&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/74GFMe0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Rokinon 8mm fisheye lens example&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;prime-lens-and-overall-favorite--100-50mm&quot;&gt;Prime lens (and overall favorite) – $100 50mm&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The number one entry-level lens rated by millions of people, the “nifty fifty”” is a lens that can’t &lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt; be bought by anyone with a digital SLR camera. The reason it’s so desirable is because it’s dirt cheap, but has amazing quality. It doesn’t take much to make photographs look professional and high quality with the 50mm lens and some decent light (like the sun).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another huge benefit to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1R1A2WP&quot;&gt;50mm&lt;/a&gt; is the low f-number of f/1.8, giving it a blurred background (bokeh). The Canon EF 50mm f/1.8 II lens allows in much more light, and a much more dramatic depth of field (so dramatic, the depth of field may be hard to control if recording video).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">What use do you have for the lens? There are many lenses to choose from the DSLR family and it can be a bit daunting when you don’t know what you’re looking for. Beginner lenses should be cheap and effective - luckily, there are a few out there that fit such criteria. To start out, you should assess why you need a lens – will you be shooting animals in nature, portraits, close-ups, or everyday use? Also, what is your budget? Often, lenses will cost more than the camera body itself. I want to preface these suggestions by saying that I have owned, used and personally recommend each of the items below. I’m not a professional photographer, but I have done some paid gigs. While these lenses may not be the best glassware ever made, they do create high quality photographs at an affordable, hobbyist-level price range. Before picking the perfect one, you must first examine what you’ll be using the lens for. There are a few major categories when deciding what type of lends you’ll be needing: Zoom lens – animal, sports, or similar photography Macro lens – extreme close-up shots Wide angle lens – realty videos and landscape photography Prime lens – no zoom, more crisp focus and image quality Let’s further examine each style. Each have their benefits for different types of photography. When you consider your use, also keep in mind the quality of glass. For example, I have a prime lens that only cost around $100 and a zoom that cost maybe two or three times that; the prime lens creates a much sharper image and has a lower f-number, allowing for more light and depth of field in the image. Now, to examine the lenses that I would consider the top qualifying for each category: Zoom Lens – $145 55-250mm Quality zoom lenses are hard to find due to the amount of glass in them, and thus making them some of the most expensive lenses to choose from. My first zoom was the 55-250mm. It has a closest focal distance of 3.6 feet or 1.1m with image stabilization and autofocus. If light isn’t an issue, this piece of glass can do a great job for its price. The Canon EF-S 55-250mm telephoto lens has an f-number of f/4.0-5.6, allowing an adequate amount of light into the sensor. There are some special offers offered from Amazon, such as a 1 year warranty. Macro Lens – $15 Extension Tubes This may have not been what you expected, but if you’re beginning into the hobby of photography or videography, I think it’s safe to assume you’re on a little bit of a budget. These extension tubes do require having a lens to start with, so you can’t expect to only pay $15 to start taking extreme closeup shots that are super sharp. These extension tubes are relatively simple; they extend your lens from your camera and keep it still, creating a zoomed-in effect that you would only expect to see with a dedicated macro lens. The great thing about these extension tubes is that it turns nearly any of your lenses into a macro lens. It is great with primes that let in a fair amount of light, such as the 50mm. Some of the features won’t be accessible on your lens (if it’s digitally controlled, as many are) while using the extension tubes because the lens itself isn’t physically connected to the camera body. It still takes great photos for a $15 addon! If you are looking for a more professional piece of glassware that’s dedicated to macro photography, check out the 100mm f/2.8 lens. Wide Angle Lens – $300-350 Sigma 10-20mm Wide angle lenses can be a bit tricky when looking for the right one because many of them are super expensive and or have a weird effect known as a fish-eye. If you’re looking to make skateboarding videos, music videos, or other types of videos that a GoProesque effect would add to the overall production, you might be interested in something like the Rokinon 8mm F3.5 Fisheye. While you get a weird effect with the lens, it is much wider and has a lower f-number, meaning it will allow more light and create more depth of field. But if you’re looking to minimize distortion and keep a majority of the picture as undistorted as possible, I recommend the Sigma 10-20mm. These lenses tend to have little or no barrel or pincushion distortion (they keep straight features straight instead of curving them). However, in these types of lenses, the rectilinear perspective creates things on the sides of the image to appear bigger than they are (almost stretching the outer edges a bit). This type of lens creates a much more exaggerated wide-angle image that distorts straight lines along the edges into more curvy lines. Initially used to study clouds with their “whole-sky”” point of view, this hemispherical perspective lens adds a very distinct effect to your photographs or video. While not practical for every event, it certainly is worth considering. Prime lens (and overall favorite) – $100 50mm The number one entry-level lens rated by millions of people, the “nifty fifty”” is a lens that can’t not be bought by anyone with a digital SLR camera. The reason it’s so desirable is because it’s dirt cheap, but has amazing quality. It doesn’t take much to make photographs look professional and high quality with the 50mm lens and some decent light (like the sun). Another huge benefit to the 50mm is the low f-number of f/1.8, giving it a blurred background (bokeh). The Canon EF 50mm f/1.8 II lens allows in much more light, and a much more dramatic depth of field (so dramatic, the depth of field may be hard to control if recording video).</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://mediaunmasked.com/assets/2016/02/OusLEXG.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Speed up youtube &amp;#038; avoid time warner ISP throttling</title><link href="https://mediaunmasked.com/tutorials/speed-up-youtube-avoid-isp-throttling/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Speed up youtube &amp;#038; avoid time warner ISP throttling" /><published>2016-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-01-13T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://mediaunmasked.com/tutorials/speed-up-youtube-avoid-isp-throttling</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mediaunmasked.com/tutorials/speed-up-youtube-avoid-isp-throttling/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;isp-throttling&quot;&gt;ISP throttling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time Warner Cable (TWC) and a few other internet providers can do a sneaky thing (probably stated in their terms of service somewhere) where they throttle your internet download speed when streaming (and uploading) a youtube (or similar stream based sites such as Netflix, Hulu, Twitch, etc.) video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have the basic Time Warner Cable package that includes phone, cable and internet. Using speedtest.net, I normally had anywhere from 1-10 mb/s download, and always under 1mb/s upload (when I was paying for 15mb/s). This is because Time Warner Cable was throttling the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Note: some speed test websites can show inaccurate results. Try using a couple unaffiliated speed testing sites.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-googles-public-dns&quot;&gt;Use Google’s public DNS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A quick tip for speeding up &lt;strong&gt;all&lt;/strong&gt; websites, even if only a little is by changing from your current, default DNS to Google’s. A DNS is essentially a phone book for the internet. When you go to a website, your computer (or router) performs a DNS lookup before it downloads it. Routers will often default to use your internet service provider’s DNS. To change your router’s DNS to Google’s public DNS for faster and more secure DNS lookups:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to your router’s home page (common one is &lt;a href=&quot;http://192.168.1.1/&quot;&gt;192.168.1.1&lt;/a&gt;) and navigate to the internet section. On this page, you should find a &lt;em&gt;Domain Name Server (DNS) Address&lt;/em&gt; header. Remove any default values (or change it to &lt;em&gt;Use These DNS Servers&lt;/em&gt;) and enter &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;8.8.8.8&lt;/code&gt; &lt;strong&gt;and/or&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;8.8.4.4&lt;/code&gt; (the second one is an alternative). Restart your router and you should be using Google’s public DNS servers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TWC may put a limit on the download, or stream, speed that you can download from sites like YouTube, Twitch, Netflix and Hulu. Each time you open a video, your computer connects to a server, one that TWC has inherently throttled. Luckily, there is an easy fix to this problem. You’ll need to block the primary connection that is requested. It will then request the default, faster, server (which will speed up the download speed tremendously).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is an short, easy method of adding this IP block using the command prompt and a longer, more user interface friendly version. They both do the same thing – hope you can follow one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;a href=&quot;/reviews/browsers/&quot;&gt;which browser is best&lt;/a&gt; for speed and performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;short-version&quot;&gt;Short version&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start -&amp;gt; type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;cmd&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/iSDNPAV.png&quot; alt=&quot;Open cmd.exe from windows 7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Type the following into the command prompt:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;netsh advfirewall firewall add rule name=&quot;TWC SUCKS&quot; dir=in action=block remoteip = 173.194.55.0/24,206.111.0.0/16 enable=yes&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hit enter (You should get a confirmative ‘Ok.’)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/3rvH6Xt.png&quot; alt=&quot;Hit enter to get a confirmation message&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it. Now it should default to the faster IP when requesting certain sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Note: to undo this, type the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;netsh advfirewall firewall delete rule name=&quot;TWC SUCKS&quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;long-version&quot;&gt;Long version&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start -&amp;gt; type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;firewall&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Zo8HQFo.png&quot; alt=&quot;type firewall into start menu&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click InBound Rules (top left)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/L2JDXcG.png&quot; alt=&quot;inbound rules&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click new rule&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/rbxj94X.png&quot; alt=&quot;Click new rule&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check custom -&amp;gt; next&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/srk7Z0W.png&quot; alt=&quot;Select custom radio button&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check all programs -&amp;gt; next&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/cPePvWF.png&quot; alt=&quot;Select All programs and hit next&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leave the default settings -&amp;gt; Next&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/8bdpjm8.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under REMOTE IP addresses, check These IP addresses -&amp;gt; Add:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;173.194.55.0/24 206.111.0.0/16&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Vx6CKd1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Block the connextions -&amp;gt; Next&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/fnPrPr4.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep Domain, Private and Public all checked -&amp;gt; Next&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/4fMNM2i.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give it a proper name and description -&amp;gt; Finish&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/z3OqYyA.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">ISP throttling Time Warner Cable (TWC) and a few other internet providers can do a sneaky thing (probably stated in their terms of service somewhere) where they throttle your internet download speed when streaming (and uploading) a youtube (or similar stream based sites such as Netflix, Hulu, Twitch, etc.) video. I have the basic Time Warner Cable package that includes phone, cable and internet. Using speedtest.net, I normally had anywhere from 1-10 mb/s download, and always under 1mb/s upload (when I was paying for 15mb/s). This is because Time Warner Cable was throttling the internet. Note: some speed test websites can show inaccurate results. Try using a couple unaffiliated speed testing sites. Use Google’s public DNS A quick tip for speeding up all websites, even if only a little is by changing from your current, default DNS to Google’s. A DNS is essentially a phone book for the internet. When you go to a website, your computer (or router) performs a DNS lookup before it downloads it. Routers will often default to use your internet service provider’s DNS. To change your router’s DNS to Google’s public DNS for faster and more secure DNS lookups: Go to your router’s home page (common one is 192.168.1.1) and navigate to the internet section. On this page, you should find a Domain Name Server (DNS) Address header. Remove any default values (or change it to Use These DNS Servers) and enter 8.8.8.8 and/or 8.8.4.4 (the second one is an alternative). Restart your router and you should be using Google’s public DNS servers! TWC may put a limit on the download, or stream, speed that you can download from sites like YouTube, Twitch, Netflix and Hulu. Each time you open a video, your computer connects to a server, one that TWC has inherently throttled. Luckily, there is an easy fix to this problem. You’ll need to block the primary connection that is requested. It will then request the default, faster, server (which will speed up the download speed tremendously). There is an short, easy method of adding this IP block using the command prompt and a longer, more user interface friendly version. They both do the same thing – hope you can follow one of them. Check out which browser is best for speed and performance. Short version Start -&amp;gt; type cmd Type the following into the command prompt: netsh advfirewall firewall add rule name=&quot;TWC SUCKS&quot; dir=in action=block remoteip = 173.194.55.0/24,206.111.0.0/16 enable=yes Hit enter (You should get a confirmative ‘Ok.’) That’s it. Now it should default to the faster IP when requesting certain sites. Note: to undo this, type the following: netsh advfirewall firewall delete rule name=&quot;TWC SUCKS&quot; Long version Start -&amp;gt; type firewall Click InBound Rules (top left) Click new rule Check custom -&amp;gt; next Check all programs -&amp;gt; next Leave the default settings -&amp;gt; Next Under REMOTE IP addresses, check These IP addresses -&amp;gt; Add: 173.194.55.0/24 206.111.0.0/16 Next Block the connextions -&amp;gt; Next Keep Domain, Private and Public all checked -&amp;gt; Next Give it a proper name and description -&amp;gt; Finish</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://mediaunmasked.com/assets/2016/02/twc.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Chrome vs Firefox vs Edge vs Opera</title><link href="https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/browsers/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chrome vs Firefox vs Edge vs Opera" /><published>2016-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2016-01-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/browsers</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/browsers/">&lt;p&gt;It’s safe to say that Microsoft Edge, Mozilla Firefox, Google Chrome, Safari and Opera are the most popular browsers. When choosing a browser, it’s important to remember that popularity brings with it developers for &lt;a href=&quot;/resources/chrome-plugins-for-everyday-use/&quot;&gt;plugins and extensions&lt;/a&gt;. Your internet browser is limited not necessarily by the performance of the browser, but by the apps and extensions offered by the developers in the community. For instance, Google’s Chromecast requires you to be using their browser, Chrome, in order to use the device for your TV. They offer the streaming extension in the Chrome store for laptop/desktop computing. While most plugins for all the top browsers are universal, there are some exclusive extensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this breakdown, I’ll be comparing the top 4 internet browsers that people use: &lt;strong&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Microsoft Edge&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Opera&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;design--functionality&quot;&gt;Design &amp;amp; functionality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the nitty-gritty tech specs, let’s consider the layout and design of each browser. While they share many aspects of each other, they have small distinctions that could possibly (though I suggest to not let it) make or break your browser decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extensions are a necessity for browsers, which is why it might be harder to get behind some of the lesser-known browsers (they might not have the extension you want). All four browsers have plugins/addons/extensions and the popular ones are probably supported on all platforms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All modern browsers will have an address bar, search bar (some combined), tabs (and a new tab screen), bookmarks, and unique elements for that browser. Your &lt;em&gt;toolbar&lt;/em&gt; is minimal, to give you more room to view the website, which is the whole point of a web browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col s12 m6 pull-left&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Chrome&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;pull-left inline s3&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/WVSfir7.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Chrome is simple. You've got at the top your tabs, address bar, and optional bookmarks. Extensions are put to the side of the address bar and can be collapsed under the &quot;more&quot; menu in the top right of the browser. To the left of the search bar, you've got your standard back and forward buttons as well as refresh with an optional home button. Chrome was given an update to follow their design standard, Material Design (at least the icons).&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;What you type in the search bar, or &lt;i&gt;omnibox&lt;/i&gt; will do a search on your set default search engine or other sites based on what you type before it. For instance: with the Wolfram|Alpha extension, just type &lt;code&gt;= [tab]&lt;/code&gt; before your search and it will do a Wolfram|Alpha search. Extensions like this are one of the reasons Chrome is so popular.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col s12 m6 pull-left&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Microsoft Edge&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;pull-left inline s3&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/zODZ1mD.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Microsoft Edge has a very similar vibe with a little different layout. The UI is more rectilinear (which I prefer) and is quite simple. Beyond the basic elements you'd expect from a browser, there is the built-in ability to essentially draw on any website, save that screen shot, and export it to One Note or share it online directly. Edge is the default browser in Windows 10 (you can change this).&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Microsoft wants to integrate their products together into one universal system, which is great in theory. While most of their products are solid and fine for most, you may find that you like certain aspects of competitive products better.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;row&quot;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col s12 m6 pull-left&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Firefox&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;pull-left inline s3&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/wwspFha.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Firefox mirrors the features of the others, and has a lot of similar extensions that Chrome has. If there's an extension on Chrome that you like, chances are it's been developed for Firefox (similar to how apps are developed for both Android and iOS) or vice-versa. Firefox has its own UI which scrolls smoothly and performs quite well.&lt;/p&gt; 
    &lt;p&gt;These browsers will all feel very similar from a design perspective, so you'll only find the largest differences in their performances features, interface, and your overall preference.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class=&quot;col s12 m6 pull-left&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Opera&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;pull-left inline s3&quot; src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/iJJXtKr.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Opera has a sleek look to it, unique way to view videos while you browse, and a built-in ad blocker. It's got a &lt;i&gt;speed dial&lt;/i&gt; which is just like the other new tab screens with links to your most visited/favorite websites, but it also features a news option that will display recent stories from news sites.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Opera have created a new browser called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opera.com/computer/neon&quot;&gt;Neon&lt;/a&gt;. With it, they are trying to simplify and improve what traditional browsers look like and how they behave. I encourage you to play around with it - the UI is original and has things like built-in screen shots that extend the out-of-box functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;benchmarks&quot;&gt;Benchmarks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through several benchmarking tests online, we can decide which browser is the best. The best considering factors such as speed, usability, features, and so on. The benchmarking programs will give a score. The score is only relevant if you understand each element in the scoring system or you look into what makes up the score. Otherwise, the scores are only significant based on comparison to the other browsers. That’s what I’ll be doing — comparing each browser to the next. This way, we can find out which of the 5 most popular browsers comes out on top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;google-octane-javascript&quot;&gt;Google Octane (Javascript)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The JavaScript Benchmark Suite for the modern web&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone knows the web, it’s Google. &lt;a href=&quot;http://chromium.github.io/octane/&quot;&gt;Google Octane&lt;/a&gt; is part of the Chromium project on github. They put together this benchmark test that runs multiple Javascript functions that represent the complexity of modern web apps on modern desktop and mobile browsers. This is Octane version 2, which adds in a few more tests that version 1 didn’t include. &lt;b&gt;Chrome&lt;/b&gt; had the highest score on Octane’s tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;row isoItems&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Chrome - &lt;b&gt;24385&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/YNcThUl.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chrome 44 Octane Javascript performance score is 24385&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Edge - 23893
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/dqOizpL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Microsoft Edge Octane Javascript performance score is 23893&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 
              
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Opera - 23200
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Ywpoa6e.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Opera Octane Javascript performance score is 23200&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 
                    
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Firefox - 22179
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/BGwc2PN.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Firefox Octane Javascript performance score is 22179&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
  Speedometer (Responsiveness)
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Browserbench offers a web browser benchmarking tool called &lt;a href=&quot;http://browserbench.org/Speedometer/&quot;&gt;Speedometer&lt;/a&gt;. This benchmark tests the responsiveness of apps by simulating user interactions in demo web applications. Essentially, it tests the speed and functionality that a browser can be expected to perform when interacting with a website. The final result is runs/minute, but we'll be using this number relative to each other browser to see which can handle the most. &lt;b&gt;Opera&lt;/b&gt; had the highest scores on the Speedometer testing.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;row isoItems&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Opera - &lt;b&gt;51.82&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/h4&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/oiBfKZs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Opera responsive speedometer result is 51.82&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 
        
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Chrome - 38.20
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/42Ecy85.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Goole Chrome Browserbench responsive speedometer result is 38.20&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 
              
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Firefox - 32.40
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/WyHiAwd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Firefox Browserbench responsive speedometer result is 32.40&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 
                    
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Edge - 26.25
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/1Ik166J.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Microsoft Edge Browserbench responsive speedometer result is 26.25&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
  Jetstream (Javascript)
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Browserbench also has another browser benchmarking tool called &lt;a href=&quot;http://browserbench.org/JetStream/&quot;&gt;Jetstream&lt;/a&gt;, which measures javascript efficiency rather than the responsiveness of a web application. Similar to Octane, but it’s never a bad idea to have multiple sources for benchmarking. &lt;b&gt;Edge&lt;/b&gt; had the highest scores on the Jetstream tests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;row isoItems&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Edge - &lt;b&gt;166.29&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/oXg4P4m.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Microsoft Edge Browserbench JetStream result is 166.29&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Chrome - 136.28
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/k3UhxwT.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Goole Chrome Browserbench JetStream result is 136.28&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 
      
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Opera - 128.99
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/veBE11V.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Opera Browserbench JetStream result is 128.99&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 
            
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Firefox - 119.75
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/u8btSaH.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Firefox Browserbench JetStream result is 119.75&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
  HTML5 Test
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, &lt;a href=&quot;http://html5test.com/&quot;&gt;HTML5 Test&lt;/a&gt; tests how well browsers support HTML 5, the markup language of the internet. It takes into consideration things like file support for different video/audio/image codecs, HTML 5 standard elements, forms, 2D and 3D graphic rendering, performance, security, and other components. If a browser shows support for a tested standard, it’s given some points - which are totaled up to give their final scores. &lt;b&gt;Chrome&lt;/b&gt; had the highest scores on the HTML 5 tests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;row isoItems&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Chrome - &lt;b&gt;526&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/2y5ut0y.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Chrome HTML 5 test support specific elements and components&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Opera - 525
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/c28zX8W.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Opera HTML 5 test support specific elements and components&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 
              
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Edge - 458
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/d7YjrB0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Microsoft Edge HTML 5 test support specific elements and components&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 
                    
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Firefox - 478
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/gQkVAuv.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Firefox HTML 5 test support specific elements and components&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;
  Browserscope (security)
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.browserscope.org/&quot;&gt;Browserscope&lt;/a&gt; is a browser benchmark test for security, network, and other categories. Below is a list of popular browsers they have tested on their site, with &lt;b&gt;Chrome&lt;/b&gt; scoring the highest and Firefox in second.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;row isoItems&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Common browsers
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/BL7eFmL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Browserscope results&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;
  Browsermark (CSS animations)
&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://web.basemark.com&quot;&gt;Browsermark&lt;/a&gt; runs the browser through multiple CSS animation flex tests to see how your browser handles 2D and 3D CSS animations. &lt;b&gt;Opera&lt;/b&gt; won this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;row isoItems&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Opera - &lt;b&gt;5488&lt;/b&gt;
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/XTKvdYE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Browsermark Opera CSS animations benchmark result is 5488&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 
        
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Chrome - 5287
      &lt;/h4&gt;

      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/bmNPVDa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Browsermark Chrome CSS animations benchmark result is 5287&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 

  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Firefox - 4175
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/SM54cRc.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Browsermark Firefox CSS animations benchmark result is 4175&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt; 
                                            
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Edge - 2786
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      &lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/5mRAku5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Browsermark Edge CSS animations benchmark result is 2786&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
  Verdict
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/b&gt; won 3 of the 6 tests, Opera won 2, and Edge won 1. Performance seems to be leaning towards Chrome, with Opera in a close second. Eventually, you should consider more than just the performance of a browser. Do you like how it behaves (scrolling is different in Firefox than it is in Chrome, for example)? Is there extension support? Etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most internet browsers are, more or less, the same, except for one factor: the community. The community, the users, is what makes or breaks a browser’s success. For that reason, I think Google Chrome is the best browser for an internet experience. That is, app/extension developers will prioritize the most commonly used browser to develop for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Google’s browser will always be popular as long as they maintain it to industry standards and keep their name on it. With that, any product or extensions developed by Google will only be available through Google (like &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/2odO6Tt&quot;&gt;Chromecast&lt;/a&gt;). So for an overall great experience for years to come, I think Google takes the gold with Chrome. It may not be the best, but it’s up to industry standards and with it comes the diverse field of developers. All of these browsers work fine. They all have a rather similar format and no more toolbars that take up 20% of the screen (with modern high resolution displays).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;
  Download browsers
&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;collection&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.com/intl/en/chrome/browser/desktop/index.html&quot; class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;Google Chrome&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/new/&quot; class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;Mozilla Firefox&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.opera.com/&quot; class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;Opera&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/download/details.aspx?id=48126&quot; class=&quot;collection-item&quot;&gt;Microsoft Edge&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It’s safe to say that Microsoft Edge, Mozilla Firefox, Google Chrome, Safari and Opera are the most popular browsers. When choosing a browser, it’s important to remember that popularity brings with it developers for plugins and extensions. Your internet browser is limited not necessarily by the performance of the browser, but by the apps and extensions offered by the developers in the community. For instance, Google’s Chromecast requires you to be using their browser, Chrome, in order to use the device for your TV. They offer the streaming extension in the Chrome store for laptop/desktop computing. While most plugins for all the top browsers are universal, there are some exclusive extensions. In this breakdown, I’ll be comparing the top 4 internet browsers that people use: Google Chrome, Microsoft Edge, Mozilla Firefox, and Opera. Design &amp;amp; functionality Before we get into the nitty-gritty tech specs, let’s consider the layout and design of each browser. While they share many aspects of each other, they have small distinctions that could possibly (though I suggest to not let it) make or break your browser decision. Extensions are a necessity for browsers, which is why it might be harder to get behind some of the lesser-known browsers (they might not have the extension you want). All four browsers have plugins/addons/extensions and the popular ones are probably supported on all platforms. All modern browsers will have an address bar, search bar (some combined), tabs (and a new tab screen), bookmarks, and unique elements for that browser. Your toolbar is minimal, to give you more room to view the website, which is the whole point of a web browser. Chrome Chrome is simple. You've got at the top your tabs, address bar, and optional bookmarks. Extensions are put to the side of the address bar and can be collapsed under the &quot;more&quot; menu in the top right of the browser. To the left of the search bar, you've got your standard back and forward buttons as well as refresh with an optional home button. Chrome was given an update to follow their design standard, Material Design (at least the icons). What you type in the search bar, or omnibox will do a search on your set default search engine or other sites based on what you type before it. For instance: with the Wolfram|Alpha extension, just type = [tab] before your search and it will do a Wolfram|Alpha search. Extensions like this are one of the reasons Chrome is so popular. Microsoft Edge Microsoft Edge has a very similar vibe with a little different layout. The UI is more rectilinear (which I prefer) and is quite simple. Beyond the basic elements you'd expect from a browser, there is the built-in ability to essentially draw on any website, save that screen shot, and export it to One Note or share it online directly. Edge is the default browser in Windows 10 (you can change this). Microsoft wants to integrate their products together into one universal system, which is great in theory. While most of their products are solid and fine for most, you may find that you like certain aspects of competitive products better. Firefox Firefox mirrors the features of the others, and has a lot of similar extensions that Chrome has. If there's an extension on Chrome that you like, chances are it's been developed for Firefox (similar to how apps are developed for both Android and iOS) or vice-versa. Firefox has its own UI which scrolls smoothly and performs quite well. These browsers will all feel very similar from a design perspective, so you'll only find the largest differences in their performances features, interface, and your overall preference. Opera Opera has a sleek look to it, unique way to view videos while you browse, and a built-in ad blocker. It's got a speed dial which is just like the other new tab screens with links to your most visited/favorite websites, but it also features a news option that will display recent stories from news sites. Opera have created a new browser called Neon. With it, they are trying to simplify and improve what traditional browsers look like and how they behave. I encourage you to play around with it - the UI is original and has things like built-in screen shots that extend the out-of-box functionality. Benchmarks Through several benchmarking tests online, we can decide which browser is the best. The best considering factors such as speed, usability, features, and so on. The benchmarking programs will give a score. The score is only relevant if you understand each element in the scoring system or you look into what makes up the score. Otherwise, the scores are only significant based on comparison to the other browsers. That’s what I’ll be doing — comparing each browser to the next. This way, we can find out which of the 5 most popular browsers comes out on top. Google Octane (Javascript) The JavaScript Benchmark Suite for the modern web If anyone knows the web, it’s Google. Google Octane is part of the Chromium project on github. They put together this benchmark test that runs multiple Javascript functions that represent the complexity of modern web apps on modern desktop and mobile browsers. This is Octane version 2, which adds in a few more tests that version 1 didn’t include. Chrome had the highest score on Octane’s tests. Chrome - 24385 Edge - 23893 Opera - 23200 Firefox - 22179 Speedometer (Responsiveness) Browserbench offers a web browser benchmarking tool called Speedometer. This benchmark tests the responsiveness of apps by simulating user interactions in demo web applications. Essentially, it tests the speed and functionality that a browser can be expected to perform when interacting with a website. The final result is runs/minute, but we'll be using this number relative to each other browser to see which can handle the most. Opera had the highest scores on the Speedometer testing. Opera - 51.82 Chrome - 38.20 Firefox - 32.40 Edge - 26.25 Jetstream (Javascript) Browserbench also has another browser benchmarking tool called Jetstream, which measures javascript efficiency rather than the responsiveness of a web application. Similar to Octane, but it’s never a bad idea to have multiple sources for benchmarking. Edge had the highest scores on the Jetstream tests. Edge - 166.29 Chrome - 136.28 Opera - 128.99 Firefox - 119.75 HTML5 Test As the name suggests, HTML5 Test tests how well browsers support HTML 5, the markup language of the internet. It takes into consideration things like file support for different video/audio/image codecs, HTML 5 standard elements, forms, 2D and 3D graphic rendering, performance, security, and other components. If a browser shows support for a tested standard, it’s given some points - which are totaled up to give their final scores. Chrome had the highest scores on the HTML 5 tests. Chrome - 526 Opera - 525 Edge - 458 Firefox - 478 Browserscope (security) Browserscope is a browser benchmark test for security, network, and other categories. Below is a list of popular browsers they have tested on their site, with Chrome scoring the highest and Firefox in second. Common browsers Browsermark (CSS animations) Browsermark runs the browser through multiple CSS animation flex tests to see how your browser handles 2D and 3D CSS animations. Opera won this one. Opera - 5488 Chrome - 5287 Firefox - 4175 Edge - 2786 Verdict Google Chrome won 3 of the 6 tests, Opera won 2, and Edge won 1. Performance seems to be leaning towards Chrome, with Opera in a close second. Eventually, you should consider more than just the performance of a browser. Do you like how it behaves (scrolling is different in Firefox than it is in Chrome, for example)? Is there extension support? Etc. Most internet browsers are, more or less, the same, except for one factor: the community. The community, the users, is what makes or breaks a browser’s success. For that reason, I think Google Chrome is the best browser for an internet experience. That is, app/extension developers will prioritize the most commonly used browser to develop for. Google’s browser will always be popular as long as they maintain it to industry standards and keep their name on it. With that, any product or extensions developed by Google will only be available through Google (like Chromecast). So for an overall great experience for years to come, I think Google takes the gold with Chrome. It may not be the best, but it’s up to industry standards and with it comes the diverse field of developers. All of these browsers work fine. They all have a rather similar format and no more toolbars that take up 20% of the screen (with modern high resolution displays). Download browsers Google Chrome Mozilla Firefox Opera Microsoft Edge</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://mediaunmasked.com/assets/2016/02/ByQzdAH.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">20 Chrome plugins for everyday use</title><link href="https://mediaunmasked.com/resources/chrome-plugins-for-everyday-use/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="20 Chrome plugins for everyday use" /><published>2015-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://mediaunmasked.com/resources/chrome-plugins-for-everyday-use</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mediaunmasked.com/resources/chrome-plugins-for-everyday-use/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;chrome-plugins&quot;&gt;Chrome plugins&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use Google Chrome as your main web browser, you should also be taking advantage of plugins/extensions that can be made by anyone. These make the browser infinitely more powerful and will help you with everyday browsing and should save you time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;row isoItems&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Checker Plus for Gmail
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/checker-plus-for-gmail/oeopbcgkkoapgobdbedcemjljbihmemj&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/xYvAnHX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Gmail email checker plugin extension for Google Chrome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/checker-plus-for-gmail/oeopbcgkkoapgobdbedcemjljbihmemj&quot;&gt;Checker Plus for Gmail&lt;/a&gt; is my most used plugin for Chrome. For me, email is an important form of communication and speedy replies are important factor in it. My phone shoots off a notification when I get an email, but I spend quite a bit of time on the computer, so this plugin does just that: checks my email every so often and sends a notification when I get something new. There are plenty of these, but I found this one to be the most extensive, customizable, and simple. By donating the author some money, you can unlock the branding and other features — worth it!&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        AlienTube - Reddit comments on Youtube &amp;amp; Vimeo
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/alientube-for-youtube/opgodjgjgojjkhlmmhdlojfehcemknnp&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/KVUGCAy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Reddit comments on youtube with AlienTube for youtube&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        Ahh comments: can’t live with them, can’t live without them. Unfortunately, Google hasn’t quite got the filtration formula that we’ve come to love on Reddit. Reddit’s value priority system seems to be the most effective I’ve seen online and is certainly better than anything YouTube has to offer. To remedy this, there’s a plugin (&lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/alientube-for-youtube/opgodjgjgojjkhlmmhdlojfehcemknnp&quot;&gt;AlienTube&lt;/a&gt;) that replaces the YouTube comments section with those from subreddits that have posted a link to the video. You can click between the different submitted subreddits or click over to the YouTube comments if you so dare.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Google Dictionary
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/google-dictionary-by-goog/mgijmajocgfcbeboacabfgobmjgjcoja&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/xInTH2k.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Simple double click dictionary plugin extension for Google Chrome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        With &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/google-dictionary-by-goog/mgijmajocgfcbeboacabfgobmjgjcoja&quot;&gt;Google Dictionary&lt;/a&gt;, double click any word to get the definition right then and there. I remember in school, we’d have to look through a paper book to find the definition of a word. With this plugin, you don’t even have to search for the word on a website. Just double click to get the definition right there. IT will even pronounce it if you want!&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Hangouts
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hangouts/nckgahadagoaajjgafhacjanaoiihapd&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/MnikXG2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Free SMS texting with Google Hangouts&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hangouts/nckgahadagoaajjgafhacjanaoiihapd&quot;&gt;Google Hangouts&lt;/a&gt; have taken over Google’s free calling service, Voice. You can still call and text people for free with a unique phone number, but it’s now merged with Google Hangouts. This plugin adds an item to your taskbar and will popup when someone calls or texts you. If you miss the call, you still get an email with the message and (attempted) transcript, so things haven’t changed much. &amp;lt;3 Google overlords
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Keepa
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/keepa-price-tracker/neebplgakaahbhdphmkckjjcegoiijjo&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/SBMHfsm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Keep track of Amazon item's previous prices with Keepa plugin extension for Google Chrome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/keepa-price-tracker/neebplgakaahbhdphmkckjjcegoiijjo&quot;&gt;Keepa&lt;/a&gt; is pretty similar to camelcamelcamel, in that it gives you the price history of an item on Amazon. It also gives you the option be notified when the price lowers. It’s helpful if you want to ensure you’re not buying an item that just jumped up or to encourage you to buy if the item is at a low price.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Lazarus
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/lazarus-form-recovery/loljledaigphbcpfhfmgopdkppkifgno&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Ypi4OeG.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Save online forms with Lazarus plugin extension for Google Chrome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/lazarus-form-recovery/loljledaigphbcpfhfmgopdkppkifgno&quot;&gt;Lazarus&lt;/a&gt; has saved me on more than one occasion. Have you ever filled in a form only to find it timed out or you lost internet connection? This happened to me a few times when I was filling out scholarship applications. You only have to write thousands of words on multiple prompts and then have it all deleted because there was a timeout session a few times before you think of searching for such a plugin. Let me save you the headache: get the plugin, now!&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Google Cast
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/google-cast/boadgeojelhgndaghljhdicfkmllpafd&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/25fChCN.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Cast movies and tv shows to your TV with Google Chrome's plugin extension: Google Cast&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        If you have a Chromecast, then you probably have &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/google-cast/boadgeojelhgndaghljhdicfkmllpafd&quot;&gt;Google Cast&lt;/a&gt;. If you don’t have a Chromecast, you’re probably paying too much for cable.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Hover Zoom
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hover-zoom%2B/pccckmaobkjjboncdfnnofkonhgpceea&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/vlo6Eh2.png&quot; alt=&quot;View images on sites without clicking on them. Just hover with the Hover Zoom plugin extension for Google Chrome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        If you frequent Reddit, &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/hover-zoom%2B/pccckmaobkjjboncdfnnofkonhgpceea&quot;&gt;this plugin&lt;/a&gt; will become one of your best friends. Simply, it pulls the imgur image (or other) and pops it up in your current window, so you can view images without leaving reddit. It will work on other sites or you can limit it (or block) to specific sites that you want images to pop up on.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Reddit Enhancement Suite
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/reddit-enhancement-suite/kbmfpngjjgdllneeigpgjifpgocmfgmb&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/onCgGg4.png&quot; alt=&quot;Reddit night view and other modifications with Reddit Enhancement Suite Google Chrome plugin extension&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        This is another redditor must-have. &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/reddit-enhancement-suite/kbmfpngjjgdllneeigpgjifpgocmfgmb&quot;&gt;Reddit Enhancement Suite (RES)&lt;/a&gt; extends the site extraordinarily well from the interface enhancements to simple functionalities you didn’t know you wanted. Easily switch between accounts, &amp;#8220;night&amp;#8221; viewing mode, and a few other things.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Reddit Hide Sidebar
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/reddit-hide-sidebar/kmhljmlnmkpkfidhceknegheeplgmngg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/7XmkQwi.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Make Reddit responsive by hiding the sidebar with Reddit Hide Sidebar plugin extension for Google Chrome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        Reddit sucks on phones because it’s not &amp;#8220;responsive,&amp;#8221; meaning the text is small and you have to pinch to zoom in and all that jazz. Even if it does look fine on your phone, sometimes if you have side-by-side windows, it can be a little cramped. With that, there’s a plugin that lets you &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/reddit-hide-sidebar/kmhljmlnmkpkfidhceknegheeplgmngg&quot;&gt;hide the sidebar&lt;/a&gt;, taking advantage (on most subreddits) of the full width of your screen for the content. It conveniently adds a show/hide link by the other important links in the top right.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Video Speed
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/video-speed/fnjmlegmhldjolpmcfjhooibnchlafgg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/7Fjc1Cr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Speed up and slow down Youtube with hotkeys with the Video Speed plugin extension for Google Chrome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        Similar to SpeakIt, sometimes you just need the information, but can’t or don’t want to consume it the traditional method — but this time for videos. &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/video-speed/fnjmlegmhldjolpmcfjhooibnchlafgg&quot;&gt;Video Speed&lt;/a&gt; lets you change the playback speed of both YouTube and Vimeo videos with the bracket keys, [ and ]. This is currently a function built into YouTube’s player, but it’s simpler with the hotkeys. I’ve used this to speed through school lectures in half (or less) the time than it would’ve taken otherwise.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Looper for YouTube
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/looper-for-youtube/iggpfpnahkgpnindfkdncknoldgnccdg&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/vBKOxOv.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Speed up and slow down Youtube with hotkeys with the Video Speed plugin extension for Google Chrome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        This little plugin adds a button below YouTube videos to &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/looper-for-youtube/iggpfpnahkgpnindfkdncknoldgnccdg&quot;&gt;enable looping&lt;/a&gt; for a number of times or infinitely. It’s basic, but it does its purpose exactly.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        SpeakIt
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/speakit/pgeolalilifpodheeocdmbhehgnkkbak&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/saPzvdB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Read article out loud with SpeakIt plugin extension for Google Chrome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        Sometimes you can't or just don't want to read an article, but you want to know the information in it. With &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/speakit/pgeolalilifpodheeocdmbhehgnkkbak&quot;&gt;SpeakIt&lt;/a&gt;, you can have a (very robotic) voice read it to you when you select text and click the right click option.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Stylish
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/stylish/fjnbnpbmkenffdnngjfgmeleoegfcffe&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/vDotfxJ.png&quot; alt=&quot;Change website styles with Stylish plugin extension for Google Chrome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/stylish/fjnbnpbmkenffdnngjfgmeleoegfcffe&quot;&gt;Stylish&lt;/a&gt; extends all websites to your personal styling. With a little bit of CSS knowledge, you can hide specific elements, or alter others on any website.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Web Timer
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/web-timer/ggnjbdfgigejghknieofeahaknkjafim&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Hh2MCMr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Keep track of time spent on websites with Web Timer plugin extension for Google Chrome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/web-timer/ggnjbdfgigejghknieofeahaknkjafim&quot;&gt;Web Timer&lt;/a&gt; just tracks the time you spend on any website and then gives you a graph. It’s not particularly helpful, but it is really interesting to see how much time is spent on each website. I like to hide the button and just keep it activated so it continues to collect data and then I can view it at a later point when more time has passed.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Whatfont?
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/whatfont/jabopobgcpjmedljpbcaablpmlmfcogm&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/HDvcIYe.png&quot; alt=&quot;Easily find out what font is on a website with What font? plugin extension for Google Chrome&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/whatfont/jabopobgcpjmedljpbcaablpmlmfcogm&quot;&gt;Whatfont&lt;/a&gt; is handy when, well… you want to know what font a website is using. It’s a tool-tip style overlay that gives you the font of the hovered element. Clicking the elements gives you more information, like the font size, line height, where the font is served, the hex, etc. There are over 400k users of Whatfont.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;!-- .isoItems.row --&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;cta&quot; style=&quot;background: url(&amp;quot;https://i.imgur.com/vXfgEH4.jpg&amp;quot;) center center; height: 375px&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.domain.com/join/index.bml?AffID=835697&quot; class=&quot;waves-effect waves-light btn-large blue&quot;&gt;Get your own website up and running&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing about the internet is that a lot of it is open for development; open for improvement for everyone. If there’s not an extension, site, app, etc. then you can just build it yourself (or pay someone to do it for you). Google understands this and allows their browser, Chrome, to be developed and improved upon by the public through extensions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know if there are any plugins that you absolutely love so I can check them out!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Chrome plugins If you use Google Chrome as your main web browser, you should also be taking advantage of plugins/extensions that can be made by anyone. These make the browser infinitely more powerful and will help you with everyday browsing and should save you time. Checker Plus for Gmail Checker Plus for Gmail is my most used plugin for Chrome. For me, email is an important form of communication and speedy replies are important factor in it. My phone shoots off a notification when I get an email, but I spend quite a bit of time on the computer, so this plugin does just that: checks my email every so often and sends a notification when I get something new. There are plenty of these, but I found this one to be the most extensive, customizable, and simple. By donating the author some money, you can unlock the branding and other features — worth it! AlienTube - Reddit comments on Youtube &amp;amp; Vimeo Ahh comments: can’t live with them, can’t live without them. Unfortunately, Google hasn’t quite got the filtration formula that we’ve come to love on Reddit. Reddit’s value priority system seems to be the most effective I’ve seen online and is certainly better than anything YouTube has to offer. To remedy this, there’s a plugin (AlienTube) that replaces the YouTube comments section with those from subreddits that have posted a link to the video. You can click between the different submitted subreddits or click over to the YouTube comments if you so dare. Google Dictionary With Google Dictionary, double click any word to get the definition right then and there. I remember in school, we’d have to look through a paper book to find the definition of a word. With this plugin, you don’t even have to search for the word on a website. Just double click to get the definition right there. IT will even pronounce it if you want! Hangouts Google Hangouts have taken over Google’s free calling service, Voice. You can still call and text people for free with a unique phone number, but it’s now merged with Google Hangouts. This plugin adds an item to your taskbar and will popup when someone calls or texts you. If you miss the call, you still get an email with the message and (attempted) transcript, so things haven’t changed much. &amp;lt;3 Google overlords Keepa Keepa is pretty similar to camelcamelcamel, in that it gives you the price history of an item on Amazon. It also gives you the option be notified when the price lowers. It’s helpful if you want to ensure you’re not buying an item that just jumped up or to encourage you to buy if the item is at a low price. Lazarus Lazarus has saved me on more than one occasion. Have you ever filled in a form only to find it timed out or you lost internet connection? This happened to me a few times when I was filling out scholarship applications. You only have to write thousands of words on multiple prompts and then have it all deleted because there was a timeout session a few times before you think of searching for such a plugin. Let me save you the headache: get the plugin, now! Google Cast If you have a Chromecast, then you probably have Google Cast. If you don’t have a Chromecast, you’re probably paying too much for cable. Hover Zoom If you frequent Reddit, this plugin will become one of your best friends. Simply, it pulls the imgur image (or other) and pops it up in your current window, so you can view images without leaving reddit. It will work on other sites or you can limit it (or block) to specific sites that you want images to pop up on. Reddit Enhancement Suite This is another redditor must-have. Reddit Enhancement Suite (RES) extends the site extraordinarily well from the interface enhancements to simple functionalities you didn’t know you wanted. Easily switch between accounts, &amp;#8220;night&amp;#8221; viewing mode, and a few other things. Reddit Hide Sidebar Reddit sucks on phones because it’s not &amp;#8220;responsive,&amp;#8221; meaning the text is small and you have to pinch to zoom in and all that jazz. Even if it does look fine on your phone, sometimes if you have side-by-side windows, it can be a little cramped. With that, there’s a plugin that lets you hide the sidebar, taking advantage (on most subreddits) of the full width of your screen for the content. It conveniently adds a show/hide link by the other important links in the top right. Video Speed Similar to SpeakIt, sometimes you just need the information, but can’t or don’t want to consume it the traditional method — but this time for videos. Video Speed lets you change the playback speed of both YouTube and Vimeo videos with the bracket keys, [ and ]. This is currently a function built into YouTube’s player, but it’s simpler with the hotkeys. I’ve used this to speed through school lectures in half (or less) the time than it would’ve taken otherwise. Looper for YouTube This little plugin adds a button below YouTube videos to enable looping for a number of times or infinitely. It’s basic, but it does its purpose exactly. SpeakIt Sometimes you can't or just don't want to read an article, but you want to know the information in it. With SpeakIt, you can have a (very robotic) voice read it to you when you select text and click the right click option. Stylish Stylish extends all websites to your personal styling. With a little bit of CSS knowledge, you can hide specific elements, or alter others on any website. Web Timer Web Timer just tracks the time you spend on any website and then gives you a graph. It’s not particularly helpful, but it is really interesting to see how much time is spent on each website. I like to hide the button and just keep it activated so it continues to collect data and then I can view it at a later point when more time has passed. Whatfont? Whatfont is handy when, well… you want to know what font a website is using. It’s a tool-tip style overlay that gives you the font of the hovered element. Clicking the elements gives you more information, like the font size, line height, where the font is served, the hex, etc. There are over 400k users of Whatfont. Get your own website up and running Conclusion The best thing about the internet is that a lot of it is open for development; open for improvement for everyone. If there’s not an extension, site, app, etc. then you can just build it yourself (or pay someone to do it for you). Google understands this and allows their browser, Chrome, to be developed and improved upon by the public through extensions. Let me know if there are any plugins that you absolutely love so I can check them out!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://mediaunmasked.com/assets/2015/05/SBMHfsm.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Royalty free images</title><link href="https://mediaunmasked.com/resources/list-of-sites-for-royalty-free-images-for-commercial-and-noncommercial-use/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Royalty free images" /><published>2015-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://mediaunmasked.com/resources/list-of-sites-for-royalty-free-images-for-commercial-and-noncommercial-use</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mediaunmasked.com/resources/list-of-sites-for-royalty-free-images-for-commercial-and-noncommercial-use/">&lt;p&gt;The following list of sites are places where you can search or browse for royalty free images (some are completely free of charge) that you can put in your own videos, slideshows, or other project - commercially or noncommercially (read the description of the item you pick to see what needs to be done in terms of attribution).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;royalty-free-images&quot;&gt;Royalty-free images&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;row isoItems&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Google
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com/images&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/zmzzPAa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: All&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://google.com/images&quot;&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt; is the most popular and powerful search engine around, so why not search images and filter them to only ones that are marked Creative Commons or otherwise?&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Flickr
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/creativecommons/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/tYHhc9P.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: All&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        One of the largest image-sharing communities is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.flickr.com/creativecommons/&quot;&gt;Flickr&lt;/a&gt;, which lucky for us, allows its users to mark what sort of license / sharing they want to give to others.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;row isoItems&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Pixabay
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/fidCtAL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Vectors, photos, art illustration&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://pixabay.com/&quot;&gt;Pixabay&lt;/a&gt; is a clean search engine that results in some nice images you can use for anything - commercial or otherwise. There different sizes and meta data for each image (similar to Flickr).&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Stock Photos
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://stockphotos.io/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/HB7BD0V.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Stock photos, people &amp;amp; nature, illustrations&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://stockphotos.io/&quot;&gt;Stock photos&lt;/a&gt; also maintains a sleek design while offering a Pinterest-like user interface for you to browser the images.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Pexels
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pexels.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/OahIjXy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Photos (5 new per day)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pexels.com/&quot;&gt;Pexels&lt;/a&gt; has some very high quality images that you can browse through or search for.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Wallhaven
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://alpha.wallhaven.cc/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/NtFhAWX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Wallpapers&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://alpha.wallhaven.cc/&quot;&gt;Wallhaven&lt;/a&gt; has some nice wallpaper-style images that you could use for different purposes.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Stock Up
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitebuilderreport.com/stock-up&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/F1xf4OB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Curated stock photos&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sitebuilderreport.com/stock-up&quot;&gt;Stock Up&lt;/a&gt; curates 21 free stock photo websites all in one search engine that is constantly updated.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Finda Photo
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://finda.photo/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/CfqnS62.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Wallpapers&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        With perhaps the best domain name for finding images, &lt;a href=&quot;http://finda.photo/&quot;&gt;finda.photo&lt;/a&gt; allows you to search free stock images &amp;#8220;from them all&amp;#8221; by color, category, source, or words.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Stock Snap
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://stocksnap.io/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/7tslerz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Wallpapers&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://stocksnap.io/&quot;&gt;Stock Snap&lt;/a&gt; is another repository for high quality imagery that you can search specific keywords. All photos are free from copyright restrictions (no attribution required).&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Multicolr
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://labs.tineye.com/multicolr/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/tsmCoXI.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: All, search by color pallet&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://labs.tineye.com/multicolr/&quot;&gt;Multicolr&lt;/a&gt; is more of a fun project that lets you pick a few colors and it will automatically search 20 million Creative Commons photos on Flickr for the images that match your color pallet - amazing!&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Creative Commons
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://search.creativecommons.org/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ICMCZHY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: All&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://search.creativecommons.org/&quot;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt; is merely a license for content in the digital age. Their website has a function to search many popular sites like Flickr, Google Images, Youtube, and a few more sites for content that uses a CC license.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Unsplash
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/B8l9osG.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: All&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://unsplash.com/&quot;&gt;Unsplash&lt;/a&gt; has a repository of royalty free images that you can use, but also offers to send you 10 new ones every day if you make an account on their website.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Gratisography
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gratisography.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Woe5aoW.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Animals, natures, objects, people, urban, fun&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gratisography.com/&quot;&gt;Gratisography&lt;/a&gt; is made by Ryan McGuire at Bells Design, so the quantity of photographs might not be as infinite as other sources, but the quality is excellent.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Little Visuals
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://littlevisuals.co/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/pzjdcUd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: All&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://littlevisuals.co/&quot;&gt;Little Visuals&lt;/a&gt; can deliver zipped photos to your email or you can search or browse through their previous weeks shots.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Life of Pix
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lifeofpix.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/dkgk5Tm.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: City, beach, animals, food, nature, etc.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lifeofpix.com/&quot;&gt;Life of Pix&lt;/a&gt; is another blog-roll style site that delivers new photographs that you can use, royalty free.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Picjumbo
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://picjumbo.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/3iQzTaL.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Art&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://picjumbo.com/&quot;&gt;Picjumbo&lt;/a&gt; offers free photos for download, but if you want their whole collection in one go, you will have to pay for them.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        New Old Stock
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://nos.twnsnd.co/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/bHSrfXy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Vintage photos from public archive, historic&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://nos.twnsnd.co/&quot;&gt;New Old Stock&lt;/a&gt; has vintage photos from the public archive that are free of known copyright restrictions, meaning you can use these images for your own projects.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Free Refe Real Life Photos
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://getrefe.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/zEZifwV.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Refe, people interactive with technology&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://getrefe.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;This Tumblr&lt;/a&gt; page has royalty free natural looking photos of people interactive with technology.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Get Refe
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://getrefe.com/downloads/category/free/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/5Wr377r.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Refe, people interactive with technology&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://getrefe.com/downloads/category/free/&quot;&gt;Get Refe&lt;/a&gt; offers images (some free, some paid) of people interactive with technology and other, natural looking images.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Picography
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://picography.co/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/55kA7HH.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Art, graffiti, buildings, food, etc.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://picography.co/&quot;&gt;Picography&lt;/a&gt; shows artistic shots in the city that you can use however you like.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Foodies Feed
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://foodiesfeed.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/dZYmEPt.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Food&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;https://foodiesfeed.com/&quot;&gt;Foodies Feed&lt;/a&gt; is your one-stop shop for food photographs. Search by categories such as breakfast, pasta, meat &amp;amp; fish, healthy, drinks, etc.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Magdeleine
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://magdeleine.co/browse/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/3e6Wpim.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Art, people, animals, food, technology, nature&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://magdeleine.co/browse/&quot;&gt;Magdeleine&lt;/a&gt; has free hand-picked images with easy to see CC licenses as you hover over the image you've selected (attribution, none, etc.).&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Jay Mantri
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://jaymantri.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/7eeTCKh.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Landscapes, animals, food, buildings, etc.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://jaymantri.com/&quot;&gt;Jay Mantri&lt;/a&gt; wants us to &amp;#8220;make magic&amp;#8221; with these &amp;#8220;free pics&amp;#8221; on his Tumblr page. Don't let him down!&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Viintage
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://viintage.com/genre/free-vintage-public-domain-images/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/NBaLdAF.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Vintage graphics, public domain&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://viintage.com/genre/free-vintage-public-domain-images/&quot;&gt;Viintage&lt;/a&gt; has some pretty neat vintage graphics that are in the public domain. Check them out, if nothing more than for inspiration.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        ISO Republic
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://isorepublic.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/3CvkEuH.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Architecture, nature, people, textures&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://isorepublic.com/&quot;&gt;ISO Republic&lt;/a&gt; offers a premium subscription for their stock photos, but there are also free images, which is nice.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Travel Coffee Book
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://travelcoffeebook.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/jqWdaLe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Travel (global)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://travelcoffeebook.com/&quot;&gt;Travel Coffee Book&lt;/a&gt; has travel images from around the world that you can use for anything (CC0).&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Splitshire
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.splitshire.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/cayjhgv.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: People, landscape, nature, etc.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.splitshire.com/&quot;&gt;Split Shire&lt;/a&gt; has some beautiful photos that you can use commercially. You can also download their entire collection for a price.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Public Domain Archive
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://publicdomainarchive.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/j61Ijfj.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Vintage &amp;amp; modern stock photos&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://publicdomainarchive.com/&quot;&gt;Public Domain Archive&lt;/a&gt; updates their site every week with new vintage and modern stock imagery that you're free to use.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Raumrot
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://raumrot.com/photo-set-landing/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ytXbjVy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Lifestyle&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://raumrot.com/photo-set-landing/&quot;&gt;Raumrot&lt;/a&gt; has lifestyle images that look nice, as do most of the other sites listed on this page.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Jeshoots
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeshoots.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/uw2B9rB.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Devices, people, animals, food&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeshoots.com/&quot;&gt;Jeshoots&lt;/a&gt; gives us some images of devices, people, food, and other categories that anyone can use, for free.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Free Nature Stock
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://freenaturestock.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/DDRcsjq.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Nature&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://freenaturestock.com/&quot;&gt;Free Nature Stock&lt;/a&gt; is another Tumblr page, but mostly oriented towards nature stock photos (who knew?!).&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Stokpic
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://stokpic.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/TdgKsea.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Abstract, animals, food, nature, etc.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://stokpic.com/&quot;&gt;Stokpic&lt;/a&gt; sends its subscribers new photos each week or you can browse them based on their categories.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Kaboompics
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://kaboompics.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/jgj0gEa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Abstract, city, fashion, food, landscape&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://kaboompics.com/&quot;&gt;Kaboompics&lt;/a&gt; is yet another blogroll style site that has some free images that you can use. Who needs a camera, anyway?&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Resplashed
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.resplashed.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/Ip0yCVH.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Landscape, city, nature, animals, etc.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.resplashed.com/&quot;&gt;Resplashed&lt;/a&gt; has hundreds of images you can filter through with their search engine.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Splashbase
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.splashbase.co/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/VYTn13Q.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: All, public domain&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.splashbase.co/&quot;&gt;Splashbase&lt;/a&gt; is another searchable index of images (and videos) that you can download and use in your project.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        MMT
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://mmt.li/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/9wNMkMS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Buildings, nature, food, etc.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://mmt.li/&quot;&gt;MMT&lt;/a&gt;, created by Jeffrey Betts, offers his photos under the CC0 license.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Startup Stock Photos
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://startupstockphotos.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/IZqOGYA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Startup stock photos&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://startupstockphotos.com/&quot;&gt;Startup Stock Photos&lt;/a&gt; has the images you need to make your fake startup. Need a developer writing on a macbook while drinking coffee or someone writing on a whiteboard? This is the site for you.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Crow the Stone
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://crowthestone.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/fwlR1nf.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Nature, animals, plants, etc.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://crowthestone.com/&quot;&gt;Crow the Stone&lt;/a&gt; is a Tumblr blog that gives you some nice imagery that you can use however you wish.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Moveast
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://moveast.me/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/LKHI3MV.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: Travel, Portuguese&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://moveast.me/&quot;&gt;Moveast&lt;/a&gt; is a travel blog of a Portuguese man moving who thinks every photo should be free. Interesting!&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Snapwire Snaps
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://snapwiresnaps.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/2C6ypC6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: People, objects, animals, city, etc.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://snapwiresnaps.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Snapwire Snaps&lt;/a&gt; is another blog that gives you a few new photos every week via email or you can simply browse through the site to see some cool images taken by some professional photographers.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Albumarium
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://albumarium.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/ES1DpaO.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: People, objects, animals, city, etc.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://albumarium.com/&quot;&gt;Albumarium&lt;/a&gt; lets you browse their albums or search for specifics. I love their website - beautiful and easy to use!&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        HiResStock
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://hiresstock.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/drPNVth.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: All&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://hiresstock.com/&quot;&gt;HiResStock&lt;/a&gt; has many different categories that you can browse through, blogroll style.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  
  &lt;li class=&quot;item col s12 m6 l4&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;card-panel&quot;&gt;
      &lt;h4&gt;
        Cupcake
      &lt;/h4&gt;
      
      &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://cupcake.nilssonlee.se/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/WtvDJCK.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Royalty free images for commercial or noncommercial use&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;/p&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;i&gt;Type: All&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
      
      &lt;h6&gt;
        &lt;a href=&quot;http://cupcake.nilssonlee.se/&quot;&gt;Cupcake&lt;/a&gt; has photos taken by Jonas Wimmerström who puts up some photos with a CC0 license so we're all free to use them how we like.&lt;br /&gt;
      &lt;/h6&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;cta&quot; style=&quot;background: url(&amp;quot;https://i.imgur.com/foFNXLK.jpg&amp;quot;) center center; height: 375px&quot;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pond5.com/?ref=mediaunmasked&quot; class=&quot;waves-effect waves-light btn-large white blue-text&quot;&gt;View HD royalty free images&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusion: there are many, many, &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; sites that offer royalty free, CC0, or otherwise free to use images that we can put on our websites or other projects. The problem now becomes searching for what you’re looking for from these different sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find a site that has a style you like and you’re a photographer, consider giving them your email so you can get sent a few photos every week as inspiration. Otherwise, just bookmark this page and refer back to it when you need a photo or some inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The following list of sites are places where you can search or browse for royalty free images (some are completely free of charge) that you can put in your own videos, slideshows, or other project - commercially or noncommercially (read the description of the item you pick to see what needs to be done in terms of attribution). Royalty-free images Google Type: All Google is the most popular and powerful search engine around, so why not search images and filter them to only ones that are marked Creative Commons or otherwise? Flickr Type: All One of the largest image-sharing communities is Flickr, which lucky for us, allows its users to mark what sort of license / sharing they want to give to others. Pixabay Type: Vectors, photos, art illustration Pixabay is a clean search engine that results in some nice images you can use for anything - commercial or otherwise. There different sizes and meta data for each image (similar to Flickr). Stock Photos Type: Stock photos, people &amp;amp; nature, illustrations Stock photos also maintains a sleek design while offering a Pinterest-like user interface for you to browser the images. Pexels Type: Photos (5 new per day) Pexels has some very high quality images that you can browse through or search for. Wallhaven Type: Wallpapers Wallhaven has some nice wallpaper-style images that you could use for different purposes. Stock Up Type: Curated stock photos Stock Up curates 21 free stock photo websites all in one search engine that is constantly updated. Finda Photo Type: Wallpapers With perhaps the best domain name for finding images, finda.photo allows you to search free stock images &amp;#8220;from them all&amp;#8221; by color, category, source, or words. Stock Snap Type: Wallpapers Stock Snap is another repository for high quality imagery that you can search specific keywords. All photos are free from copyright restrictions (no attribution required). Multicolr Type: All, search by color pallet Multicolr is more of a fun project that lets you pick a few colors and it will automatically search 20 million Creative Commons photos on Flickr for the images that match your color pallet - amazing! Creative Commons Type: All Creative Commons is merely a license for content in the digital age. Their website has a function to search many popular sites like Flickr, Google Images, Youtube, and a few more sites for content that uses a CC license. Unsplash Type: All Unsplash has a repository of royalty free images that you can use, but also offers to send you 10 new ones every day if you make an account on their website. Gratisography Type: Animals, natures, objects, people, urban, fun Gratisography is made by Ryan McGuire at Bells Design, so the quantity of photographs might not be as infinite as other sources, but the quality is excellent. Little Visuals Type: All Little Visuals can deliver zipped photos to your email or you can search or browse through their previous weeks shots. Life of Pix Type: City, beach, animals, food, nature, etc. Life of Pix is another blog-roll style site that delivers new photographs that you can use, royalty free. Picjumbo Type: Art Picjumbo offers free photos for download, but if you want their whole collection in one go, you will have to pay for them. New Old Stock Type: Vintage photos from public archive, historic New Old Stock has vintage photos from the public archive that are free of known copyright restrictions, meaning you can use these images for your own projects. Free Refe Real Life Photos Type: Refe, people interactive with technology This Tumblr page has royalty free natural looking photos of people interactive with technology. Get Refe Type: Refe, people interactive with technology Get Refe offers images (some free, some paid) of people interactive with technology and other, natural looking images. Picography Type: Art, graffiti, buildings, food, etc. Picography shows artistic shots in the city that you can use however you like. Foodies Feed Type: Food Foodies Feed is your one-stop shop for food photographs. Search by categories such as breakfast, pasta, meat &amp;amp; fish, healthy, drinks, etc. Magdeleine Type: Art, people, animals, food, technology, nature Magdeleine has free hand-picked images with easy to see CC licenses as you hover over the image you've selected (attribution, none, etc.). Jay Mantri Type: Landscapes, animals, food, buildings, etc. Jay Mantri wants us to &amp;#8220;make magic&amp;#8221; with these &amp;#8220;free pics&amp;#8221; on his Tumblr page. Don't let him down! Viintage Type: Vintage graphics, public domain Viintage has some pretty neat vintage graphics that are in the public domain. Check them out, if nothing more than for inspiration. ISO Republic Type: Architecture, nature, people, textures ISO Republic offers a premium subscription for their stock photos, but there are also free images, which is nice. Travel Coffee Book Type: Travel (global) Travel Coffee Book has travel images from around the world that you can use for anything (CC0). Splitshire Type: People, landscape, nature, etc. Split Shire has some beautiful photos that you can use commercially. You can also download their entire collection for a price. Public Domain Archive Type: Vintage &amp;amp; modern stock photos Public Domain Archive updates their site every week with new vintage and modern stock imagery that you're free to use. Raumrot Type: Lifestyle Raumrot has lifestyle images that look nice, as do most of the other sites listed on this page. Jeshoots Type: Devices, people, animals, food Jeshoots gives us some images of devices, people, food, and other categories that anyone can use, for free. Free Nature Stock Type: Nature Free Nature Stock is another Tumblr page, but mostly oriented towards nature stock photos (who knew?!). Stokpic Type: Abstract, animals, food, nature, etc. Stokpic sends its subscribers new photos each week or you can browse them based on their categories. Kaboompics Type: Abstract, city, fashion, food, landscape Kaboompics is yet another blogroll style site that has some free images that you can use. Who needs a camera, anyway? Resplashed Type: Landscape, city, nature, animals, etc. Resplashed has hundreds of images you can filter through with their search engine. Splashbase Type: All, public domain Splashbase is another searchable index of images (and videos) that you can download and use in your project. MMT Type: Buildings, nature, food, etc. MMT, created by Jeffrey Betts, offers his photos under the CC0 license. Startup Stock Photos Type: Startup stock photos Startup Stock Photos has the images you need to make your fake startup. Need a developer writing on a macbook while drinking coffee or someone writing on a whiteboard? This is the site for you. Crow the Stone Type: Nature, animals, plants, etc. Crow the Stone is a Tumblr blog that gives you some nice imagery that you can use however you wish. Moveast Type: Travel, Portuguese Moveast is a travel blog of a Portuguese man moving who thinks every photo should be free. Interesting! Snapwire Snaps Type: People, objects, animals, city, etc. Snapwire Snaps is another blog that gives you a few new photos every week via email or you can simply browse through the site to see some cool images taken by some professional photographers. Albumarium Type: People, objects, animals, city, etc. Albumarium lets you browse their albums or search for specifics. I love their website - beautiful and easy to use! HiResStock Type: All HiResStock has many different categories that you can browse through, blogroll style. Cupcake Type: All Cupcake has photos taken by Jonas Wimmerström who puts up some photos with a CC0 license so we're all free to use them how we like. View HD royalty free images Conclusion: there are many, many, many sites that offer royalty free, CC0, or otherwise free to use images that we can put on our websites or other projects. The problem now becomes searching for what you’re looking for from these different sources. If you find a site that has a style you like and you’re a photographer, consider giving them your email so you can get sent a few photos every week as inspiration. Otherwise, just bookmark this page and refer back to it when you need a photo or some inspiration.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://mediaunmasked.com/assets/2016/01/zmzzPAa.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Don’t Starve Review</title><link href="https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/dont-starve/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Don't Starve Review" /><published>2015-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2015-04-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/dont-starve</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://mediaunmasked.com/reviews/dont-starve/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;game-information&quot;&gt;Game information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;table class=&quot;striped&quot;&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Genres&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Survival, adventure, sandbox
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Devices&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      PC, PS4
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Co-op&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Singleplayer &amp;amp; multiplayer
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      &lt;b&gt;Price&lt;/b&gt;
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      $14.99
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t Starve is a sandbox-style game with a simple goal in mind - see how long you can stay alive. It’s pleasant to watch and it’s addicting to play. The sudden panic nightfall creates when you’ve been focusing on crafting, fighting, and scavanging will keep you wanting more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/qapqIr6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting as a character named Wilson - stranded in the middle of nowhere with nothing to your name, you’re expected to survive and explore the area. From pigs to walking eyeballs, there are many different creatures you can kill for resources in order to craft tools, clothes, structures, and more. You’ll need to craft many of these things if you expect to survive the cold, winter nights that will eventually sneak up on you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/uJda6CJ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a sandbox game, meaning the worlds are randomly generated and you’re free to roam wherever you wish. Don’t Starve is also very much a survival game, something Minecraft has popularized, which means that the overarching theme is simply to stay alive. You can achieve survival by maintaining three stats that are constantly deteriorating: &lt;strong&gt;Health&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Hunger&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Sanity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Health will go down when monsters attack you, you eat something nasty, and a few more ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your hunger slowly lowers over time and you can maintain it by eating different foods you can gather or hunt: berries, vegetables, or animal meat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your sanity is what keeps the shadow monsters at bay. When your sanity is low enough, the shadow monsters can actually hurt you. There are many ways to raise your sanity, but an easy way is to minimize the time spent in swamps and other scary areas while maximizing the time spent picking flowers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best way to learn about the game is to jump in and play. You won’t survive many days on your first try, but you’ll learn how things work and what you should build on your next go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/X3dKwx8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While you start out as Wilson, each death will reward you in experience that will unlock new characters (up to the top two characters – who can only be unlocked by playing the objective. The different characters have unique abilities that can be used to your advantage or disadvantage, depending on your preference and gameplay style.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;game-mechanics&quot;&gt;Game mechanics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s always nice to find a game that performs just as well as it looks. Don’t Starve works as expected and doesn’t take much time at all to learn the controls. The controls are pretty intuitive – you can use a mouse or keyboard to control the movements and actions or even a PS4/Xbox One/Gamepad controler (on the computer or PS4). The learning curve is low, making it more accessible to more people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/dq2eVBN.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;aesthetics&quot;&gt;Aesthetics&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the main attractionsto this game is its unique, hand-drawn, children pop-up book style. It’s visually pleasant for spectators and has a great color scheme and overall style. The fitting music is also easy on the ears and catchy. It will keep you drawn to the game almost as much as the visuals. Don’t Starve is put into a nice package that portrays a unique art style with engaging gameplay. I highly recommend getting this game for $15 and trying it out for yourself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/dftUuKX.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Game information Genres Survival, adventure, sandbox Devices PC, PS4 Co-op Singleplayer &amp;amp; multiplayer Price $14.99 Overview Don’t Starve is a sandbox-style game with a simple goal in mind - see how long you can stay alive. It’s pleasant to watch and it’s addicting to play. The sudden panic nightfall creates when you’ve been focusing on crafting, fighting, and scavanging will keep you wanting more. Starting as a character named Wilson - stranded in the middle of nowhere with nothing to your name, you’re expected to survive and explore the area. From pigs to walking eyeballs, there are many different creatures you can kill for resources in order to craft tools, clothes, structures, and more. You’ll need to craft many of these things if you expect to survive the cold, winter nights that will eventually sneak up on you. It’s a sandbox game, meaning the worlds are randomly generated and you’re free to roam wherever you wish. Don’t Starve is also very much a survival game, something Minecraft has popularized, which means that the overarching theme is simply to stay alive. You can achieve survival by maintaining three stats that are constantly deteriorating: Health, Hunger, and Sanity. Health will go down when monsters attack you, you eat something nasty, and a few more ways. Your hunger slowly lowers over time and you can maintain it by eating different foods you can gather or hunt: berries, vegetables, or animal meat. Your sanity is what keeps the shadow monsters at bay. When your sanity is low enough, the shadow monsters can actually hurt you. There are many ways to raise your sanity, but an easy way is to minimize the time spent in swamps and other scary areas while maximizing the time spent picking flowers. The best way to learn about the game is to jump in and play. You won’t survive many days on your first try, but you’ll learn how things work and what you should build on your next go. While you start out as Wilson, each death will reward you in experience that will unlock new characters (up to the top two characters – who can only be unlocked by playing the objective. The different characters have unique abilities that can be used to your advantage or disadvantage, depending on your preference and gameplay style. Game mechanics It’s always nice to find a game that performs just as well as it looks. Don’t Starve works as expected and doesn’t take much time at all to learn the controls. The controls are pretty intuitive – you can use a mouse or keyboard to control the movements and actions or even a PS4/Xbox One/Gamepad controler (on the computer or PS4). The learning curve is low, making it more accessible to more people. Aesthetics One of the main attractionsto this game is its unique, hand-drawn, children pop-up book style. It’s visually pleasant for spectators and has a great color scheme and overall style. The fitting music is also easy on the ears and catchy. It will keep you drawn to the game almost as much as the visuals. Don’t Starve is put into a nice package that portrays a unique art style with engaging gameplay. I highly recommend getting this game for $15 and trying it out for yourself!</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://mediaunmasked.com/assets/2016/02/vNVugWg-1024x576.png" /></entry></feed>